Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat.
Heat. Heat. Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Welcome. Welcome Living Mana Church
family. So good to have you here with us
today. It's always a blessing to worship
and be with you guys each and every
Sabbath. Please put in the chat where
you are viewing from. We want to say a
special welcome to you. If this is your
first time at Living Mana Church, please
put a one in the chat so we can uh tell
you a little bit about ourselves, a
little bit more, but we just want to see
where you're viewing from and say a very
special welcome to you as well.
Yes. Welcome everyone to Living Mana
Online Church. Please
uh make sure you hit the like button.
>> Yes.
>> Um and make sure you share and share.
>> Share. Yeah. Like and share.
>> Um we have a a very special and very
important Sabbath school
>> um that we're going to be doing today.
So uh we definitely want to welcome
everyone. Um thank you for joining us uh
today. Uh we believe that God has uh uh
some important things that he wants his
people
>> Yes.
>> to know to understand.
>> And so uh we're definitely looking
forward to uh to today's uh discussion.
So again welcome for those of you those
of you excuse me
that may be visiting for the first time
>> please put a one
>> and uh please living mana members make
them feel welcome.
>> Yes. Um, I want it. Let's see. We have
MacArthur, Ohio. That's Jonathan. Good
to see you. Always good to see you here,
Jonathan. Charles from Perth. That's
Australia.
>> Yes. I'm sure it's not even Sabbath
there anymore. It's it's it's Sunday.
Uh, but welcome, Charles. Happy Sabbath
to you. We have North Carolina here. Not
sure what that name is, but for North
Carolina, welcome. We have um
I'm not going to try to pronounce that
name either because I'll probably mess
it up. So, we have Oregon, welcome. So,
good to have you here. Uh Leela from
North Carolina, welcome to Living Mana
Church.
Alonso from Massachusetts. Welcome. Good
to see you here.
Welcome. And then we have Daniel um from
Europe. So, we don't know where in
Europe, but you're from Europe. So,
welcome. Always good to have everyone
here. Thomas from Madison, Alabama.
You're just so far from us right now.
Actually, you're very, very close. Uh,
Timothy, but welcome, Thomas. Timothy
from Wisconsin. Good to have you here.
Uh, El or Elis,
I said that wrong, too. Walaw Wala.
Ellis. Ellis. Okay. Ellis
>> from Walaw Wala. Good to see you. Uh,
Toronto. Andre from Toronto. Good to see
you here. Mike from Parker, Colorado.
Laura from Greenville, North Carolina.
>> And Sonnie from Fredericksburg.
>> All right.
>> Virginia.
>> Virginia. Good to see you.
>> Got Daniel from France. H. Spence from
Canada. Welcome. Good to see everyone
here today. I feel like it's going to go
on and on and on, but we're happy to
have all of you from all around the
country, United States, and all around
the world. So good to see you guys.
Welcome to Living Mana Church. We're
very happy to have you here today. And
uh can't we have to say welcome to South
Africa. Yes. Welcome to
>> um Spot Take from South Africa. I feel
like just today the names I'm just
killing the names. And as someone that
has a
>> technically I guess a hard name to other
people.
>> I don't like it when people do that.
Actually I don't mind it. I actually
when people mess my name up I'm like
it's okay.
I'll be all those all those things you
just said, but it's a tante.
>> Yes. So, yes. All right. We have you can
keep putting in the chat while we are
going to you can keep putting where
you're you're viewing from and if it's a
one, we'll we'll try to see that too and
say a very special welcome to you. Um,
but we also have some transfer
membership trans well one transfer.
So, we want to do that. And uh if you're
wanting to transfer your membership,
we'll give you more information about
that at the beginning of the divine
worship service. Um but we do have one
first reading of a membership transfer
and this is of a friend and someone
who's very already active
>> here at Living Mana Church. And we are
just so thankful for all of her
contributions.
um and and what she does for for for the
ministry already, but she's officially
ch um changing or transferring her
membership here to living mana. So, we
are excited to have Takara
I Bumas on
>> Otiano I think.
>> Oteno. Okay. Oteno Takara
because I don't know if I said that
middle part right too. Okay. Um, so we
are that's the very first reading and
she is transferring from
the Indianapolis Capitol City 7day
Adventist Church and she is one of the
leaders the the first leaders in
Hangouts. So if you've been to Hangouts
on Mon on Sundays almost said on Mondays
on Sundays we've done it twice so far.
It's been a blessing. So I invite you
next time you see us advertising for
that date you definitely want to attend.
Um, but she has been such a blessing and
we love to see your comments in the
chat. Love to hear all that you have to
share for the afterglow. She just has so
much energy, so much love for God and we
are just excited about her officially
becoming a member. Amen.
>> Of the living mana church.
>> Amen.
>> Yes. Yes. Yes. Yes. So, that was the
first reading and the second reading. It
will be next week and she will be
official.
>> Yep.
>> Official. Yes.
>> All right. All right. So,
>> t-shirt message.
>> T-shirt message.
>> You guys probably think this is a new
shirt. It actually isn't. I just I have
two that say the same thing. I just And
this one I hardly ever wear
>> and it just kind of went with today.
>> So, it's way maker, miracle worker,
promisekeeper, light in the darkness. My
God, that is who you are.
>> Yes. And so, um, as I was just thinking,
I was thinking about the Sabbath school.
I was just thinking about, all right,
Lord, what t-shirt's gonna go with
today? And I just feel like with all the
things that um not just that are
happening here in America, but that that
happen all around the world, you know,
sad things happen. There's conflict.
There's misunderstandings. There's uh
just groups of people don't agree. You
know, one's on one side, one's on the
other. That's all around the world,
right? But God is our way maker. He's
our miracle worker. He makes he's going
to bring light in the darkness and in in
confusion.
>> And you know, we know what the Bible
says or what the end of Revelation says.
He wins and this is going to
>> happen the way that he prophetically
says it's going to happen, but it's all
going to end up and it's going to be
okay. So even when we become overwhelmed
and discouraged, we just have to
remember that um God is our way maker.
>> Yeah. Amen.
>> Our way out of the darkness.
>> That's right. And he always provides a
way.
>> He always provides a way.
>> Always.
>> So with that said, we are taking uh just
a oneweek break.
>> Yep.
>> Just a oneweek break um from our
Christian Art of War, which
>> I have loved going through so slowly and
methodically with all of our guests and
our Sabbath school panel. Absolutely
love and appreciate all of them and all
that they have to share. Love our youth.
>> Yeah.
>> Love our young people. love our old
young people,
love everyone. It's been wonderful. Um
and but we're just taking one break, a
oneweek break today and we'll be back at
it next week.
>> Um I just want to say just because
>> we are um
>> at a crossroads.
>> We're at a crossroads. We are at a
crossroads, but also you know we're you
know we're this is people say this is
our brand. I don't I really don't say
that because I'm you know but I want to
say that it's not our brand but we are
>> just want to just meet people where they
where you guys are and where the world
is and if this is heavy on your mind
which I know it is because it's on
everybody's mind. Um and our church is
going through something. It's not just
our church really.
>> Is the world going through something? Uh
we're not just going to ignore it
>> and be silent and not say anything
because that's not
>> we need to talk about it.
>> Yeah. And so
>> it's like if you were diagnosed with
cancer and you're just like, "Oh, yeah.
Well, I'm not going to do anything about
it. Not going to talk about it."
>> Yeah.
>> Not going to get any help.
>> We're going to talk about it.
>> Yeah. We um
So, we're gonna, as she just said, we're
going to pivot. We're going to talk
about our church. We're going to talk
about things that are happening in our
church.
>> Yeah.
um you know, unfortunate things that I
think are happening uh in our church.
And so, you know, with the assassination
of Charlie Kirk,
>> Yeah.
>> Um you know, it's really
>> Yeah, we are going to pray, but I just
want to let everybody know, you know,
it's
>> Yeah, that's what we're talking about.
>> It's it's it's
>> been in a in a way you see a lot of
polarization happening over it.
And the polarization is happening even
in the church.
>> Yeah.
>> And in a sense
this is kind of like um
this is the Christian art of war.
>> Because
>> remember how we we we we shared earlier
in one of the earlier chapters that all
external warfare is a result of poorly
fought internal warfare.
>> And if we find ourselves
in warfare in the church. Um I think to
a great degree it is because we don't
really know how to fight the carnal
heart on the inside.
>> Right.
>> And so um we're going to be talking
about this. You know, there was um
uh the regional conferences put out a
letter.
>> Yeah. We're gonna pray that we're going
to pray. I just want to kind of Okay.
>> Yeah. let you know, hey, this is going
to be a it's going to be a, you know,
it's a needed conversation.
>> Um, and for those of you that are
watching, you might be thinking, you
know, am I, you know, what are they
going to say about this? But I think you
will be
Let's pray.
>> Yeah,
>> let's pray.
>> Let's pray.
>> All right. Heavenly Father, um, we come
before you at this time, Lord. Uh just
asking Lord that you would help us
Lord as we as we discuss what's been
going on in our church and we know that
it's happening in other churches. Um we
and among other Christians, Lord, we
pray that
you would just guide our words, guide
our thoughts, Lord, and um
Lord, may the suggestions that are made
um over this uh these next um few
moments, Lord, um
bring about healing
in the midst of division. This is our
prayer in Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen. Amen.
>> Amen.
>> Uh okay.
So, um I want to start off by uh reading
a verse in Matthew chapter 5 verse 23.
And I'm just going to read it. It won't
go up on the screen. I do have some
slides, but we're not going to put those
up uh just yet.
In Matthew 5:23, the Bible says,
"Therefore, if you bring your gift to
the altar, and there rememberth
remembrance that thy brother has ought
against thee, leave there thy gift
before the altar, and go your way.
First be reconciled to your brother, and
then come and offer your gift."
I think this is a very crucial
>> verse that we ought to take to heart
right now.
>> Um I don't think it's
it's
acceptable
to,
you know, know that there are divisions
in the church and and not find a way
to
overcome this.
and
to reconcile
>> with one another. And
this
this is the very spirit and character of
Christ.
>> He's just like, "Look, I don't even want
your worship, your gift.
>> Don't come and tell me that you love me
>> if
you can't even reconcile and love one
another."
>> He's saying, "Oo, hold your praises.
Hold your songs,
>> hold your worship,
>> hold your sermons, hold everything.
>> Go fix it.
>> And um
>> you know what that reminds me of? You're
probably going to be like, "Wow,
>> what?"
>> You're probably like, "Wow."
>> Um I don't know. It just reminds me of
like, okay, we've been married 27 years,
but you know, in all marriages, you have
little tips and things that go on.
>> So whenever if we did get into a
disagreement
>> and you had to speak,
>> you would never
>> Oh, yeah.
>> ever. ever. He never would go up on the
stage and preach before he he would come
to me first and apologize and make it
right. Like I just think you felt too
like I can't go up there and like fear.
>> I'm gonna go up there.
>> No, not even fear, but just you you want
the not fear. You wanted the Holy Spirit
to be with you and you're like, I can't
be at odds with my wife.
>> I was I wasn't going to be like I'm up
there preaching and all of a sudden my
you know
>> Well, yeah. and just for you for me to
be sitting there looking at you like
okay like you know you'd always make it
right. So I'm just saying that that's
what that reminds me of is like we we're
not to go we are to make things right
with people.
>> Yeah. Um I so I think that's very
important. I think it's it's absolutely
crucial that we that we have that
attitude. So before we even jump in and
this may be an extended Sabbath school.
Okay, before we jump in, um I'm going to
let you know that I have
>> We always have extended schools compared
to other people's, but go ahead.
>> Yeah. I'm going to I'm going to make two
appeals. Two appeals. So, please
please make sure you listen for these
two appeals. Okay?
So,
let's state the issue. Here's the issue.
Um, we know that uh last week uh Charlie
Kirk was assassinated
>> and um there was mixed reaction in the
world. Some people were celebrating his
assassination. And uh last week I I
preached a sermon and you know talked
about how God is trying to get the I
mean Satan's trying to get the whole
world
>> filled with with with wrath.
>> No matter what affiliation you are of.
>> Right.
>> Right. He's trying to get people who
deny God filled in filled with wrath.
And he's trying to fill professed
Christians with with wrath. Mhm.
>> So, you know, we addressed that, but the
issue was that for a lot of people, how
can you celebrate someone who has said
things that they have taken as racist,
right? Mhm.
>> Just to give a a a
uh you know,
let me give this example.
But so imagine like
a card holding
uh KKK person is killed and then that
person's held up. And I'm not saying
anything about, you know, this is
>> or someone who goes around saying, "I
hate all white people. I hate all white
people." And that person's killed. And
I'm not saying that, you know, Charlie
Kirk said it said said, "I hate black
people." But
>> I'm I'm trying to give you the the I'm
I'm trying to help you to understand,
>> right? The issue that people had was we
believe Charlie Kirk is has said things
that are racist, that are, you know,
derogatory in so many different ways.
How can you lift him up?
>> So that argument is happening in the
world,
>> but it's also happening in churches.
Mhm.
>> You can go online right now and find
pastors
>> preaching sermons about how in the world
>> can we be lifting up someone like this
and other pastors preaching the exact
opposite,
>> right? That he Yeah. that he was an
evangelist for
>> Yes. Yes.
>> for Christ. Mhm.
>> And so that reality has come into the
church
>> where we have seen, you know, uh,
ministry figures and all kinds of
people, you know, saying Charlie Kirk
was a martyr, da da da da da. Um, and
and let me add, this is not just white
people. There are black people in the
church that are saying this, too.
Um,
and then you have other people in the
church who are who are absolutely
blown away, devastated
>> that
people could be lifting this person up.
>> Not that they're mourning an
assassination, which I think everyone
understands is is
>> not that they're not mourning an
assassination.
>> Right. So in other words, everyone
understands of course someone's been
assassinated. That is never good.
>> That's never good.
>> But but the op the there are people in
the church who are like, but how can we
exalt a person
>> who has also
said these things
>> and taught these philosophies,
>> shared these ideas and made them
acceptable.
>> And so that is that is the crisis,
right? And so as a result of that, you
know, we have this the uh the the
regional conferences,
>> right?
>> Go ahead and you speak to Well, I was
just going to say the regional
conferences um I mean there was one one
conference released a letter
>> first
>> first and then it was um I I think the
union the the I'm not sure they regional
conferences have a
>> I should know that but I don't I don't
know if it's the the union or whatever
but Carlton Bird is the president of
that organization under all of the
>> um regional conferences and so they all
signed on including Nor Eastern which is
you know our conference that um Living
Mana is a member of and so um you know
the letter was very close to the very
the very first letter and really what
we're trying to do today is what they
called for at the end of that letter
>> is I was just saying
>> we're gonna we're going to talk about
that
>> okay yeah they want people to come
together and have
>> we're gonna
>> dialogue
>> so so basically what's going on is
what's what's happened is now you've got
the regional conferences who are saying,
"No, we're we're making a statement."
Not only because of that, but also that
this was a political figure, right? This
wasn't just a like a pastor that got
assassinated, right? This is a political
figure which represents a certain brand
of politics
that many in our church buy into.
>> Say he's an advocate.
>> When you say a political figure, you
feel like that's something.
>> Yeah. No, he's not like a senator or
whatever, but he's heavily involved in
in politics. like that's where he is
>> he's known.
>> He he believes he's
>> he's got Turning Point USA.
>> Well, he believes that his Christian
values can be he Yeah. He can to
politics to
>> Yeah.
>> force people to do things.
>> Yeah. So, you know, he says, "Hey, I'm
not a Christian nationalist. I'm a
Christian and a nationalist."
So, he he makes a distinction between
the two that he's both. But in essence,
this is all part of that Christian
nationalist movement. So all of those
things come into play, right? There's,
well, how can you support someone, you
know, lionize someone who is a Christian
nationalist? And the response is, well,
he started keeping the Sabbath. So now
you've got all these things that are
playing in, right? All these dynamics,
but the major split is along color
lines, right?
So the regional conferences
uh which represent you know the the
African-American and you know just
Jamaican Islanders just you know
>> the colored the the the black uh portion
of the church
>> in the east in the Midwest because it's
not like that on it's not like that
globally the west and yeah
>> so
this has become a very big issue
>> right because for for blacks Seventh Day
Adventists,
many black Seventh Day Ad,
right? This is not all white Adventists
on one side and all black adventists on
another side. It is
>> there's a mixed
>> multitude on both sides, but it's a
predominant,
>> right, on either side. And
>> so, black Adventists by and large are
like, "Wait a minute. How can you
support someone who was hurtful who's
been hurtful to us?
>> Right?
>> Okay. So, I want to start there. Mhm.
>> I want to start there and and
I want to again address address this
this this
issue
>> because
my first appeal
before I even make the appeal,
the first thing I want to say and I want
to start kind of drawing some some
lessons and some things that will cause
us to look in the mirror.
>> Okay. So,
first of all, I I would say this.
The way that I've seen Adventists, many
Adventists, come to the defense
of Charlie Kirk, I wish that same
spirit was extended
among ourselves.
Okay, explain.
>> In other words, there is a there is a
defense. You know, no, Charlie Kirk kept
kept the Sabbath.
>> He was a good man. Well, guess who else
keeps the Sabbath?
>> Other Seventh Day Adventists,
>> conference leaders,
>> right?
If
the the defense of
the the the willingness to defend this
person, if that same spirit was extended
to our own in defending one another
>> and not trying to, you know, how can I
find dirt? Because a lot of people are
offended. Oh, you're trying to find dirt
on Charlie Kirk. But then we often do
that with each other
>> in our own church.
>> It almost seems like there is this
selective
protection. If you agree with us, if you
are one of us, then we're going to
defend you to the to the 10th degree.
But if I don't like your position, then
I'm going to attempt to destroy your
your your character, your ministry.
We'll put it out there on the internet,
everything we can do, right?
>> Would to God that the the spirit I see
in defending someone who is not of our
faith,
>> but oh, he's a Christian. What happened
to your Christian values and more, you
know, this this man was a Christian and
we should be standing behind him? What
if we extended that same
>> love and zeal
to
you know
>> let's say Ted Wilson
>> or any other conference official
or pastor or church member and I know
Ted Wilson is not the conference
president
>> to that person if you don't if you may
not agree with them
>> absolutely
>> because these These people don't, you
know, the people that are defending
Charlie Kirk in the church know that
they don't agree with him on all things,
right? Doctrinally, I'm talking
doctrally.
>> Okay. Okay.
>> Right. He may believe we don't know what
he believes about the state of the dead
and things like that, but guess what?
They're going to they're defending him
almost as if his family.
>> Why not have that Yanico?
Why not keep that same energy
for your actual brothers and sisters who
are in the church who may not agree with
everything that you believe?
>> Why not have that same energy of love
and compassion that we can extend to
people outside the church?
>> Why not have that for
people inside the church? Right.
>> Yeah. Yes. If in other words, I'll say
it this way. God forbid someone who has
been demonized in our church has been
assassinated.
>> God forbid.
>> Would would a lot of these people say
that was God
>> that allowed that because that person,
you know, was was being shaken or
causing division, right?
>> Who knows? Maybe,
just maybe, this is God's. Don't play
with God. This it's How can we have one
spirit towards someone outside of our
church and then be so ruthless among
ourselves inside the church?
>> Yeah.
>> Go ahead. Go ahead.
>> Well, I was saying that's obviously not
um the right spirit to have. And I think
that and I know you're just starting
there.
>> Yeah, we're just starting there.
>> But I think that the biggest it's just
so hard um for
>> African-Americans or
Yeah.
Well, I was going to say it's so
difficult for them to understand how you
could just be so supportive of
um someone who, you know, even made
those type of statements or comments.
>> Yeah. And we're going to come to that
because again there's a response of,
well, he didn't say that. That was taken
out of context.
And that to me again is is you know is
quite
it's it's
you know it's
let me say it this way
we don't extend that same you're taking
out of context to other people inside
the church.
Right?
>> So in other words and I'm only talking
about consistency here. Right? So,
oh, this person said this, this, this,
this, and this. And people are
responding, oh, you're taking out out of
context. But listen, I have had people,
right, take my videos
and
attribute to me statements I never said.
>> And it doesn't matter about context or
it's just he said this and by the way,
I'm cutting him off. Mhm.
>> I don't listen to up to this morning.
>> Yeah.
>> I'm getting messages of, "Oh, pastor, I
used to listen to you, but ever since
ever since you demanded blah blah blah
blah blah," and I'm like,
>> "When did I demand that?"
>> So, we're talking about this spirit of
selective compassion, selective empathy,
selective and that needs to stop. Again,
we
put up a post last week about, hey, do
not in in in this, you know, taking um
>> you know, pulling up dirt on on Charlie
Kirk.
Yeah. Not the right thing to do right
now because this just happened today.
This just happened uh yesterday. And
just as we wouldn't want that done with
anybody, just as it shouldn't be done
with anybody else,
>> and there was there was like a big
outcry. How can you compare this person
to this person as if this person's life
was less important and less valuable to
God
than this person's life?
There's a lot I think God is revealing
how unprepared we are
for the final crisis
>> cuz we can't. And I think that the final
crisis is being held up because the
people of God, we just not ready.
And I think a lot of what has happened
over the last seven, eight, nine, ten
years is is showing and revealing what
is really hidden
>> in the hearts of people
>> in the hearts of God's people in his
church.
>> Let let me talk about um let me talk
about this because this was very
interesting to me. And again, we haven't
even gotten into I I I'm just kind of
laying the foundation to talk about,
hey, we need to step back and and look
at this because
>> there was a video put out yesterday with
uh you know, some people talking about
this whole situation and um I haven't
seen the whole video, but
you know, in looking at some of the
responses, some of the things I saw were
things like this is def this is
divisive. Mhm.
>> You can't call out a ministry because,
you know, a couple of ministries had
been mentioned by name. You know, you
know that we have issues with with these
ministries because of them lifting up
Charlie Kurt.
>> Um or what seems to be uh a blanket
glorification of him as if he didn't
offend, you know, so many people within
the Adventist church of color. And the
response was, you know, many people were
saying, "This is divisive. You're you're
bringing division into the church.
You're calling for, you know, this and
that and and this is the shaking. This
is divisive. This is you're attacking
the beloved church." And I remember
Aante Meyers
calls going out to
boycott conferences
that
um
that go
boycott conferences that are not doing
what this particular portion of the
church wants to do. So for example, if
they had any role to play in the whole
vaccine situation, there were calls to
possibly, you know, many calls
>> to we're separating or, you know,
>> uh,
>> and none of that was called divisive.
>> It was called bold,
>> courageous,
>> someone's got to stand up for the truth.
>> And I think to myself, you know, you're
dividing the church. this is purely
divisive. And I'm just like, you guys,
how are we selectively
saying in these cases, it's okay to call
for division? It's okay to call for war.
And and and it's it's couched as uh
boldness,
>> standing up for the truth. Yeah.
>> And then when it's an issue that doesn't
touch you, that doesn't feel important
to you,
>> it's you're dividing the church,
>> right? And I have to say, and I, you
know, and I encourage everyone to go and
if you
>> maybe we'll put it on our mighty
networks or something, the letter
because you need to read the letter for
yourself because they're actually saying
yes. Um, it is, you know, they have a
lot of stuff that they're they're
saying, but the final call is to
actually have conversations
with your with with your leaders, with
your pastors, like have respectful
conversations.
>> And that's what we want to talk about.
>> That's what we want to talk about.
>> So, if y'all thought we were going to
come on here and try to prove to you,
hey, this is why we're not doing that.
Like, that's the first appeal.
Let me tell you about this appeal. The
first appeal is that we need to start
talking,
>> right?
>> We we cannot
>> and to share how you to feel
respectfully.
>> That's right. We cannot continue to act
like this is not happening in our
church.
>> Right.
>> We cannot continue to just go on and be
like, oh, you know, there's not a
problem. when there clearly is a
problem.
>> And for that, I wanted to say that I can
respect what the regional conference
says did. And I say that because I've
never
there's been a lot of things.
>> It's never happened.
>> This has never happened before.
>> Now, behind closed doors
will
black Adventist talk about some things
that they feel go on in the church or
some maybe discrimination on some levels
and different things like yeah but it's
we ne they never talk about this in a
public way like maybe amongst
>> um themselves of course um but I think
this is the beginning of having a
discussion and so it may be shocking
that they did that it may be like
>> no no no they're just they're just
saying listen this is hurtful to us
this, you know, this is hurtful to us if
other ministries are
raising someone up that has been so
hurtful. Not saying,
"Let's celebrate his assassination." By
no means.
>> I mean, you really need to go back and
read the letter if you haven't seen the
letter. Um, because that's wrong.
>> And if they would and if and if if they
would have said that, I absolutely
would be would be rebuking them because
no Christian can support
>> celebrating a death on any level of of
anyone.
>> Um and it's just like, you know, as they
say, two things can be true at the same
time. Can I be saddened that a life was
taken? Yes. Can I grieve um because a
life was sensally taken? Again, yes.
Be sad for his wife and children and
family? Yes. and also at the same time
be
>> against the ideology
>> against the ide ideology that um he
spoke about.
>> Yeah.
>> So
>> you can be both of those things at the
same time. So I think the first thing
that I think is has to be revealed is
our selective
outrage,
our selective empathy,
our selective ideas of boldness.
Someone's got to stand up to the church,
right? I mean, we are people are willing
lit every day. Someone needs to stand up
to the church and the conference leaders
and the general conference because
they're doing this and this thing went
all the way to the GC. People were
wanting
someone's got to stand to the church.
Doesn't matter. There's going to be a
shaking. But then when it's an issue
that affects your brothers and sisters
in the church, you're being divisive.
>> You're being this is the shaking. We
can't do that. And I hope we're being
clear because some people might be like
I'm not familiar with all of that. Do
you understand what I'm saying? Like I
mean clear is like as far as
>> so and let me be let me be absolutely
clear when the this whole COVID vaccine
issue that's been going on in our
church. People have been calling
they've been calling for conferences to
shut down for diversion of of you know
support for for conferences. This must
go to the GC. People must resign. this,
you know, if it if it causes a split, so
be it.
>> But then
when other people are saying, "Hey,
we've got this issue with the church and
leadership and to even bring it up
is divisive, satanic.
>> What happened to unity? This is doing
nothing but destroying the church. You
cannot have both ways.
It cannot be both ways
>> and I think it's I mean because I saw
something in the chat somebody said
because this is your guys' Sabbath
school too so their comments but um
>> someone said in other and that's that's
within the church but then there's been
other situations that have happened in
in um society um that
>> and no call from
>> no call from
>> no call from leadership no
ministry saying hey we stand with you
know this was a tragedy this should
never have happened. So there's so many
different selective
>> and I have to say in defense of the
conferences in the NAD and actually the
GC these these have only been there's
only been state there's only been um
people that have spoken out from
ministries wellrespected highlevel
ministries but they're not the
conference or the NAD or the GC just for
clarification.
>> Yeah. So again we're not going to be
calling we're not calling any ministry
names. This is we're not turning a
spotlight on anybody.
>> We're talking about what's happening
among the membership
>> that is causing us to have selective
love,
>> selective outrage, selective empathy,
>> right? Selective boldness.
>> God is showing that we are
>> double-hearted, that we are not being
consistent,
>> right? We're not being consistent in how
we, you know,
we need we need to honor and and respect
Charlie. We don't have that same honor
and respect for each other,
>> right? We don't not in the church
amongst ministries. It's it's amazing.
So
our our appeal and I I'll let you talk.
>> No, no, no, no, no. Go ahead.
>> So our appeal first of all, my first
appeal is this.
Stop talking online.
Stop talking online. What do I mean by
that? Here's what I mean. Pick up the
phone
and black people
call our white friends.
White people call your black your black
friends. Get on the phone. Or if you
want to do it online, don't do it in a
public chat. say, "Hey, let's go over
here into the into our private room and
let's talk.
>> Let's go have a meal together.
>> Let's go have a meal together. If you
got to do it online, let's go have our
private discussion.
Let's
talk. This has to be a grassroots thing.
Let me let me say this and I'm going to
be quiet for a second,
>> okay?
>> Like, if I get up here, if we got on
here today to tell you this is why this
side is right and this side is wrong,
half of the people wouldn't listen."
Mhm.
>> This needs to be a grassroots thing. You
guys
get offline,
get on the phone, go have lunch, call up
that conference president, call up that
that ministry leader, call up that GC
leader, call up that lay member and say,
"Hey, listen.
I need to understand where you're coming
from." Mhm.
>> explained. Maybe I'm missing it because
in my mind I think these things are
absolutely racist.
I need to know why you don't think they
are.
>> So So explain to me maybe I'm missing
something.
>> And be genuine about that.
>> Hey, how can you how can you support
this individual or or how can you not
support this individual? And when we do
it online and in public, it's just like
all it is is you wicked he like the
level of respect that we have online. I
will tell you this,
>> there are people that have been straight
up demonic to me
>> in online conversation.
>> Like straight up just you wicked
apostate, you will pay for that sermon
you preached,
>> right? Mhm.
>> And I can guarantee you
that if we were able to get into that
online that that messenger chat.
Oh, hey, you know, oh, you know, no, I
didn't mean that. If we were in person,
oh, pastor, you know, hey, we disagree,
but you there's something different
about that keyboard warrior, right?
There's something different,
>> a lot more boldness,
>> a lot more false boldness,
>> that people have when they have these
discussions on out in the public like
this.
>> And what I'm saying is that we need a
revolution
that is grassroots. Mhm.
>> And the revolution I'm talking about
>> is the revolution of talking to one
another.
>> Not going online and going, "Here's why
this guy's wrong. Here's why this
person's wrong." Get on get on the phone
and say, "Okay,
you help me to understand
how how is this not racist?"
>> And guess what? They may explain to you.
And after they done after they're done
explaining to you, you might actually be
be like, "Oh,
that that isn't racist.
or
>> you might be like, I don't know how in
the world you could say that is racist
and then after getting on the phone
>> or just them speaking out their their
thoughts and feelings might be like, you
know what,
>> see how that's not
>> did that just come out my mouth,
>> right?
>> Did I just say that? Well, if you think
about it, all black people do.
Wow. I just said that out loud.
And so I've been talking. You go ahead.
You go ahead.
>> I forgot what it was before. No. Well,
okay. I was going to say this because
I'm just going to go back from the
beginning when you said, "Hey, uh, black
Adventist, reach out to your white
Adventist counterpart." Or maybe not
even doesn't necessarily have to be
Adventist or whatever, but
>> and white Adventists, reach out to your
black friends.
>> Right. I'm going to say this. Um because
you weren't raised in the church and I
was
>> you told me what you're about to say and
I think man that's so sad.
>> So you know I've been raised in the
church and grew up um
my my family was you know generationally
Adventist. I'm fourth generation
Adventist. So my grandmother,
great-grandmother,
three I had three great-grandparents
that were Adventist. So two great
grandmothers and one great-grandfather.
So I mean the ad, you know, so we were
all very Adventist and very active, but
was still raised in a predominantly
>> white Adventist church, white Adventist
school. Um, and then made a decision to
uh go to Pine Forge Academy in high
school. So I was, you know, I I will
never forget this. It was my freshman
year, actually. And um one of my other
freshman friends was like um
I you know I don't I don't she was like
I don't know one white
>> Adventist.
>> Her family was generationally Adventist
too. I mean like you know high level and
she and I was like huh. And as a
freshman I was 14 maybe almost 15 years
old. I was like, "That's strange," you
know, um because I just never even
thought of that. But because
>> in their world, they just she just
didn't know a white Adventist. So, what
I'm saying is like there's definitely
people who are not friends with black
adventists. Not, you know, they just
don't they're just not in that circle.
So, maybe they don't have,
I don't know, somebody to call and to
talk to. I don't know. But we definitely
>> um we stay in our corners. Yeah.
>> And we don't have those relationships.
>> Um, and there's another thing I wanted
to share. Maybe our viewing audience
doesn't know. Like your first,
>> actually, to be honest, this is Pastor
Meyer's first time working in a regional
conference. We've always worked in the
Central California Conference, and you
know, on the West Coast, they don't have
regional conferences. But not only were
you in that conference, but your
churches were white.
>> Both the first two churches were
>> completely white. Now the second church
uh became started to become more diverse
after because we were there for 11
years.
>> Um and it started to become more diverse
for sure while we were there. There was
a lot of
>> it was diverse when we got there
>> but it became more diverse.
[Laughter]
>> I mean we did have a Spanish church.
That's where we met Maria Jose. Yeah.
But actually the English speaking church
wasn't that diverse but it did
definitely become more diverse. Um, and
so I'm just saying that to say like we
and and then our second and then our
second church that we were at for seven,
eight years, it was multicultural. So we
had So maybe you were thinking of
Campbell, but Campbell was actually very
diverse. Um, but I just say all that to
say that
um, we know Adventism is split
black and white or I shouldn't say black
and white, definitely Hispanic. And you
know, we definitely have Hispanic
churches are
>> but that's more that's more language
based
>> understand but still true language based
but
>> but still there's just we're in our
separate corners is what I'm trying to
say and not like
>> and sometimes it's like I like this
worship style versus that worship style
and that's fine, you know, but we still
just don't get together to have
discussions and to come together.
>> All right. I was
>> that's why I was saying all of that
>> and I wasn't going to do this, but I'm
I'm going to do this now. I'm going to
go to my second appeal
>> and then we're going to continue on.
>> Okay.
>> Uh, no, let me hold it. I'm going to
hold my second appeal because it's going
to be an important one.
>> Okay.
>> Um, okay. So, the first thing we've
we've basically said is listen, we have
to talk start talking to one another.
>> We have to stop.
And I know there's power in going online
and saying something and hoping people
will see a different perspective, but
I think
that it is crucial
>> that we start talking with one another
in person. We've got to do it.
>> Get on the phone and call that person
and have them, you know, explain. Now,
I'm going to come to what how I would
like to see that done. Remember what
we're doing right now is we're
facilitating the church members starting
to talk.
>> If you don't have a black friend, that's
a problem.
>> It is.
>> If you don't have a white friend, that's
a problem.
>> We We got to We got to break this up
somehow.
>> We have to break this cycle somehow.
>> Okay.
>> And I And I think it needs to start at
the grassroots.
>> Let me share something with you guys.
Mhm.
>> If if we don't do this, can we can we
get our first slide up?
>> I want to bring up something
>> and while Okay, because there's comments
coming in. I just wanted to say some
things just you know some you know
somebody said we can't act like our
conferences are not intentionally
segregated.
Um
they are and they were and that
happened. You got to know the history
behind that. So, man, wish we had some
Kevin Burton here. But the history
behind that, there's there's history
behind that. Why that had to happen? So,
that happened,
>> you know, um
when
black people were not um well,
>> there's a whole lot of reason.
>> There's a whole lot of history why that
happened. And so, it was needed at that
time where there were um black
conferences um there it was needed to
be, you know, because
black people couldn't
>> we weren't being treated equal.
>> We couldn't be treated we weren't being
treated equal. We could in the church
and we couldn't even go to white
Adventist hospitals to be medically
treated. Um and so uh there just there
needed to be that at that time and
you know and at this time the regional
conferences you know I I don't know
what's I can't say the numbers before co
but prior to co were are doing so well
as far as numbers bringing in tithe all
that type of stuff I mean they support
themselves very well um and so um the
conversation of bringing them together.
That would take a lot of prayer. It's
not like they don't I I would say it's
not like they don't want to come
together, but then you're you're in a
space where um
what conference is stronger? Who has the
most people who would be president?
>> Who's going to be the president? Right.
There's so many different
>> so much there. And and I think
naturally, you know, if you're in a
church that is if you're in a in an area
that is like predominantly black, of
course your church is going to be
predominantly black, you know, right?
>> That's understand.
>> You're talking about conference
leadership,
>> right? We're talking So, there's a lot
that needs to be discussed, which is
going to come bring me to my second
appeal soon, but I'm not there yet.
>> Okay.
>> Let me say this.
Um,
for those people that support Charlie
Kirk, one of the things that that he
stood for was dialogue.
And
I think that for those who support him,
that should be your spirit.
dialogue, get on the phone,
talk, have the hard conversation
>> respectfully,
>> and there might, you know, as
Christians, God calls us to be
respectful,
>> which we're going to we're we're about
to get into about to get into this
aspect of of it as well, because
>> we need to ask ourselves, what does it
mean to be a Christian?
>> That's going to be a very important
discussion because that's a question
that a lot of people have right now.
Wait a minute. Who what does it take for
someone to be held up as as a Christian,
as a martyr? Like what is our what is
our picture as a church of what a
Christian
actually is? That's a discussion that we
need to have.
>> Let me let me share something with you.
I'm going to pull this up this slide up.
So, if we can go to our first slide. And
this may seem like some of you may not
even know about this, but I'm going to
read this. And this is just listen.
During the 1994 Rwanda genocide, Rwanda
genocide where nearly 1 million tootssie
and moderate hoous were slaughtered in
just 100 days, the Seventh Day Adventist
Church, one of the largest denominations
in Rwanda, tragically became a stage for
betrayal as some Adventists turned
against fellow believers. In places like
Mugonro, Adventist pastors and leaders
lured Tootszie church members into a
sanctuary within church walls only to
expose them to militias who slaughtered
them even on Sabbath.
Next slide.
Survivors testify that killers, some of
them Adventists, sang familiar hymns
such as, "We're marching to Zion and I'm
in the Lord's Army." as they swung
machetes and grenades inside churches,
turning sacred spaces of worship into
death chambers. Next slide.
Letters pleading for protection were
ignored or met with chilling replies
like, "Your time has come." This horror
was not born of Adventist doctrine,
but of political
tribalism.
Loyalty to ethnic identity and state
propaganda
eclipsed loyalty to Christ,
showing how easily nationalism and
tribal hatred can corrupt religious
religious faith, leading those who once
worshiped together to justify murder in
God's name.
You can take it down.
Sabbathke keeping
Ellen White Adventist quoting
unto 2300 days then shall the sanctuary
be cleansed.
>> Make sure you don't eat pork.
Seventh Day Adventists
allowed
political
tribalism
>> to swallow them up into darkness.
And what I'm saying to you church
is that if we continue on this path,
if we continue on this path,
can you put up this next slide real
quick, please?
>> Listen to what Ellen White says here.
This is prophecy, you guys.
This is prophecy. As the storm
approaches, a large class who have
professed faith in the third angel's
message, but have not been sanctified
through obedience to the truth, abandon
their position, and join the ranks of
the opposition. By uniting with the
world and partaking of its spirit, they
have come to view matters in nearly the
same light. And when the test is
brought, they are prepared to choose the
easy popular side. Men of talent and
pleasing address, who once rejoice in
the truth, employ their powers to
deceive and mislead souls. They become
the most bitter enemies of their former
brethren.
When Sabbathke keepers are brought
before the courts to answer for their
faith, these apostates are the most
efficient agents of Satan to
misrepresent and accuse them and by
false reports and insinuations stir up
the rulers against them. Let me tell you
something.
The spirit that I have watched
growing
within the church in North America
is a very
scary
spirit.
>> It is a terrifying
And the longer this spirit is allowed
to dwell in our hearts
and as long as this political tribalism
is allowed to dwell in our hearts,
what Ellen White said is going to happen
will happen and it will happen. The
question is be which side of it are you
going to be on? Are you going to be on
the side that has become so drunk with
the wine of Babylon which is a religio
political power? Will you become on the
side? Will you be on the side that is so
drunk with a religio political message?
Listen,
>> it is crazy to think
that at now listen, this wasn't just the
Adventist church,
>> right?
>> This was happening in many churches. The
sad part is that we were part of it,
>> right?
>> And so I remember when it happened back
then and I was like, how in the world
could they have ever gotten to that
place? It just blew my mind. It's like,
I I don't understand it. Now I
understand it. Mhm. Mhm.
>> Now I understand how with just a few
things
>> put in place, we could be right there.
>> Right.
So,
let's talk about righteousness for a
second
because we're setting the stage for our
talk, for your talk,
>> when you have that talk. Um, let me
share something with you. I want to go
back to the screen and I want to share
this statement from Ellen White. She
says this, "The greatest deception of
the human mind in Christ's day was that
a mare sent to the truth constitutes
righteousness.
In all human experience, a theoretical
knowledge of the truth has been proved
to be insufficient for the saving of
souls. It does not bring forth the
fruits of righteousness. A jealous
regard for what is termed theological
truth often accompanies a hatred of
genuine truth as made manifest in the
life. The darkest chapters of history
are burdened with the records of crimes
committed by bigoted religionists.
She says next slide.
She goes on to say the Pharisees claimed
to be the children of Abraham and
boasted of their possession of the
oracles of God. Yet these advantages did
not preserve them from selfishness,
malignity, greed of gain, or the basis
hypocrisy. They thought themselves the
greatest religionist of the world, but
their so-called orthodoxy led them to
crucify the Lord of glory. Let's keep
going.
The same danger still exists. Many take
it for granted that they are Christians
simply because they subscribe to certain
theological tenants.
But they have not brought the truth into
practical life. They have not believed
it and loved it. Therefore, they have
not received the power and grace that
comes through sanctification of the
truth. Men may profess faith in the
truth.
But if it does not make them sincere,
kind, patient, forbearing, heavenly
minded, it is a curse to its possessors.
And through their influence, it is a
curse to the world. Last paragraph,
please.
The Jews cultivated a spirit of
retaliation.
In their hatred of the Romans, they gave
utterance to hard denunciations and
pleased the wicked one by manifesting
his attributes. All right, you can stop
right there. You can take it down.
We need to ask ourselves as a church,
>> if Sabbathkeeping
defines righteousness,
if eating
uh if being
vegan or vegetarian defines
righteousness.
>> Because if that defines righteousness,
then everybody in the Adventist church
is righteous.
If that defines holiness, if that
defines what Christianity is, then
everybody in the Adventist church is
good to go.
>> But we know that everybody in the
Adventist church is not good to go.
>> I want to go to the next slide and I'm
going to read another statement to you.
And guys, we got to be so careful. Let
me just read.
This is from the 1940s. Something
happened with the Adventist church
again. his time in Germany.
And I want you to note what Adventists
were saying about Hitler in Germany.
A refreshing, this is a quote now, a
refreshing, enlivening, and renewing
Reformation spirit is blowing through
our German lands. This is a time of
decision, a time of such opportunities
for a believing youth as has not been
for a long time. The word of God and
Christianity shall be restored to a
place of honor. This was the Adventist
church in Germany praising Hitler. Let's
keep reading. Another example expressing
enthusiasm for the Nazi state was
William Mueller who went so far as to
label Hitler as chosen by God for the
office of chancellor and praising his
similarity with Adventist health reform.
quote,
"As an anti-alcoholic non-smoker and a
vegetarian, he is closer to our view of
health reform than anybody else."
Next slide, please.
While continuing the traditional
emphasis on health, on healthful living,
Adventist publications soon adopted
elements of the Nazi racial agenda. A
curious path led from led from karus the
caring for the less fortunate and the
weak to eliminating of the elimination
of the weak as the work of God. The
positive result of these changes was the
mainstreaming of Adventism as the state
promoted health living healthy living
and family values through church
publications. Nevertheless, slowly but
surely, the Adventist health message
adopted the vogue undertones, giving it
a twist and changing the original intent
of health reform, morphing it into what
the state dictated and not what
scripture taught. Why do I read this
quote?
Because in Germany, in Hitler's Germany,
Adventists
looked at Hitler's vegetarianism
as an opportunity
to spread
the three angels messages.
>> Now, what I'm saying is this,
>> so forgive me for my lack of history
knowledge. So, there were avenists that
joined Hitler's movement.
Wow.
I just I'm just sorry. I just never I
just Okay. Well, I I just didn't
>> Not only you, there are others watching
right now who are like, "Wait, what?"
>> Yeah. I just didn't.
>> And praise God. Yeah. After Hitler's
fall, they repented. They were like, "We
don't know what we were thinking."
>> I don't know what you was thinking
either. Yeah.
>> Praise God. They came to their senses.
We don't This is I'm not talking about
members. I'm talking about from the
president down.
>> Wow.
>> And it wasn't just the Adventist church.
Please again don't you know for somebody
watching man y'all adventists are crazy.
No. No.
>> No. I'm just Christians in general.
>> It was Christians in general. But the
fact that
>> sad
>> 2300 day Sabbathkeeping
Ellen White quoting
Adventist could have gotten caught up
>> in the name of righteousness.
Truth and morality are going to be
restored as a result of this
administration.
How can you not be on board with this?
We have
>> because biblically to like take it out
like so destroy the Jews and all this is
going to be restored like that's insane.
>> And so what I'm saying what I'm saying
please do not get me wrong. Do not
anybody walk away from here and be like
oh pastor Myers compared this person to
Hitler. I didn't do that.
>> No.
>> And and and if you do that at all
>> please before you go just remember the
just remember the word context. Mhm.
>> And there's not even any context needed
because everything I've just said, I've
just I'm going back to the example
of why it is unsafe to simply say that
to join our
to join our interests
or to declare something is righteous
just because or holy just because
an individual, whoever the individual
might be, happens to agree with us on a
particular doctrine. That's the whole
point. I'm not saying that the person
agree agreeing with us on the doctrine
is not a great thing. Oh, great. But
what I'm saying is that we need to be
careful that we don't give a blanket
endorsement.
>> Are you with me?
>> We're not giving a blanket endorsement
just because.
Okay.
So,
with these things
in mind, I think that you all need to
talk. We all need to talk.
>> Mhm.
>> I got on the phone with someone
yesterday
>> and it was a hard conversation.
>> Couple days ago.
>> Yeah. A couple days ago. It was a hard
conversation.
>> Let me say this. I'm going to give you
an example, okay? Like,
>> I'm gonna talk about my brother.
My brother knew that I had his back.
He knew that. And I knew that he had my
back. All of our all of the brothers,
>> my two older brothers, my younger
brother, if someone does something, if
someone did, back in the day, if someone
did something to offend my brother,
>> they're going to have to answer to me,
too.
In our church,
in our church,
we are supposed to be brothers,
which means that I'm expecting if
something were ever to happen that, you
know, would affect my Hispanic brothers
>> or my white brothers or my Asian
brothers
>> because y'all are my brothers.
best know that I have your back.
>> Know that if some crazy decree came
forth today that you know all white
people should be put in jail.
Guess who's going to be in jail with
you?
>> Guess who's going to be standing having
your back like no y'all are not doing
that. Mhm.
>> And so
when when that bond of brotherhood is
broken, right? Am I my brother's keeper?
When that spirit is broken where it's
like, you know what? I know that's
happening to y'all, but that's none of
my business. You know, yeah, y'all may
be hurt, but uh whatever. That's very
hurtful. I
>> I can tell you right now
that in the black community of
Adventism,
it is not so much rage as it is hurt.
>> And
>> it's hurt. It's wait a minute. I thought
we were brothers
>> and disappointment.
>> How come you're not defending us? How
come you're not saying hey, no, no, no,
no, no. How come you're not doing that?
And that
>> is the issue. So when I'm saying get on
the phone, right? I'm so saying to the
black person, listen, get on the phone
with that white person. Be like, hey,
fellow white Adventist, help me to
understand like do you are do you not
understand the pain
>> that my people have suffered and are
still suffering?
>> What what pain?
What what pain? Mhm.
>> If we say what pain that that's a
serious problem because now you you are
denying the experience, right? You're
saying no, your experience is made up.
Your experience is make believe.
>> Right.
>> Right. Your experience doesn't matter.
And that's a hard thing to hear.
>> Wait, what? You mean the stuff that my
parents went through and I went through?
Wait, that's my fault?
or it's it's it's not a big issue. It's
not a big deal to you.
>> And when people feel like you don't care
about them, you're not empathetic about
them, they're not going to want to hang
around with you.
>> And just circling back to
>> I know I keep talking.
>> I know,
>> but I'll just say this to them.
>> On the other hand,
>> don't just say you're just gonna say
that because you're not going to just
say that. for for my white brothers and
sisters, you might be like, I don't
understand, like, you know,
how can you not be sympathizing
with the fact that this man is dead or
any other issue that might be on the
table?
>> Well, I'm going to say that right there.
Can I say this right here?
>> And they don't It's not that they're not
sympathizing, right?
>> No, it's not. No, nobody wants to see
somebody killed or dead or anything like
that.
But I just want to say like, you know,
go, let me let you finish your point and
then I'm gonna circle back down to that.
>> So, I'm gonna say this, right? I don't
know how many of you know who Hebrew
Israelites are. So, Hebrew Israelites
>> are are are
>> I didn't know until the day you like
jumped out of the almost moving car to
go speak to one of them.
>> Yeah. So, there are black people who who
happen to believe that they're the true
Jews,
>> number one. And number two, that and not
all of them, but most of them believe
that all white people are going to be
lost.
>> They're irredeemable,
>> right?
>> They are going to be lost.
That that is satanic.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. It's not biblically true.
>> It's satanic,
>> right? It's just not.
>> And I'm going to stand it's mean. So
you'll never hear me say,
"Well, listen guys, what it's context.
They don't really hate, but they're
Christians.
They don't really hate white people.
It's just context. You got to understand
there." See, no, no, no, no. Listen.
They're not saying,
"Now, I'm just not going to personally
do that. There might be some people that
do that and might really believe it's
context." Okay, fine.
I know that I'm personally not going to
do that. You will never hear me say and
a Hebrew Israelite.
>> And for the most part, black black
Christians do not defend Hebrew Israel.
They do not.
>> That's right.
>> They argue with them. They all
>> absolutely
>> you will never
I will defend my white brothers and
sisters because they are my brothers and
sisters and they are children of God. I
will defend them against Hebrew
Israelites all day long. Mhm.
>> And even though I might agree with the
Hebrew Israelites that by and large
the white
in this the history of white of white
people in America and slavery is real
and exists today.
That does not represent all white
people.
>> We have gotten better in this country.
the grievances of these people. And I
can deal with their grievances. What I'm
not going to deal with
is calling an entire race something
and not saying that's racist.
>> You're not going to hear it from me.
>> Right now, many white people don't even
know who Hebrew Israelites are. Y'all be
like, "Wait, what? We
>> They're a large group. They're not super
large, but they are a lot of young black
people joining this this this movement.
Young black men joining this movement
>> and they know the Bible or can quote the
Bible
>> and they claim they claim to be
followers of Jesus.
>> Most Christians, period, they can quote
the Bible, memorize the Bible,
>> and they will never say that they hate
white people. They're just saying
they're just of the devil. It's just a
It's an objective fact.
>> Not going to be saved,
>> right? It's an objective fact. It's not,
hey, I'm not angry. I'm not It's just an
objective fact that
>> they're lost.
>> All white people are lost. All white
people are are are demonic. They are of
Satan. Just look around.
>> And to them, it's an objective reality.
>> So, we have to stand against hate no
matter what side of the aisle it's on.
>> Yeah. I'm not going to call his name,
but there's a popular black guy right
now who, you know, is all over the
YouTube, and he his disparaging remarks
about white people go viral.
>> Well,
>> you're not you're not going to see me
>> supporting
this individual, right?
>> So, the point I'm making is I know I've
cut I've never cut you off so much.
I think I'm getting you back for all the
all the
>> Anyway,
>> so
>> that's funny.
>> So
when when when your brothers
>> and you know I have a lot to say.
>> You do. Yeah. When your brothers see
that, wait a minute, you're supporting
something that we find offensive and
then you say, "No, it's not offensive."
And we're like, "But wait a minute,
we're us. You can't tell us we're not
us. And you can't tell us we're not
offended.
there is a minimizing
this is how it's received right and so
it it behooves us to get on the phone
and say hey do you understand like how I
feel about this and maybe I never
understood it that way and I think the
more we have these discussions the
better off
we will be there are some people who who
purposely did not tune in they knew I
was going to do this purpose didn't tune
in because
>> oh there's some that have tuned in for
that
>> there's some that have tuned in of
because they're waiting for that video
clip.
>> Yeah. Oh, yeah. They're waiting. Well,
they probably found a few.
>> They probably found found it already.
>> They'll take they'll mistake some of the
I mean, I'm kind of thinking that.
>> Anyway, they already have the clip, so
I'm not going to say
>> they they
>> even though if they take if they mistake
if they take it and make it what I think
they want to make it, like if they want
to try to put Charlie Kirk and equals
Hitler, they're wrong. They're lying.
Yeah. Because we didn't say that by any
means. But what about the same and this
is what I'm saying the same demand that
we have that that these people have for
context
>> context
>> we're willing to do to ignore that thing
when we deal with each other
>> and that's a scary thing
>> and okay so I
>> now I'm gonna get into the discussion
>> honestly I can't even I can't even go
back too far I can't remember what I was
gonna say way back but it's okay but um
this is something because I think like
what you're saying, it's important to
have those conversations with
white Christian brothers and sisters and
with black, you know, Christian brothers
and sisters that you guys have those
conversations together. Um, and you
know, because then you can understand a
little bit more and have real empathy
like, okay, you know what? I've never
really tried to understand where you're
coming from. are kind of just like
either grew up in this bubble and just
always just discuss these things with,
you know, people who look like me or
whatever. You know, I just saw a
comment, you know, Carrie, she said
something. I was like, "Wow, I would
never hear that." Um, but I guess her
circle she heard it and she's not, you
know, racist by any means. Um, but that
that she's heard, you know, white
Christian people say they don't see
anything wrong with being racist at a
certain level against black people.
Like, we would never hear that type of
thing. That's not what I was going to
even uh begin to say. But I was just
like, you know, when you think of I've
heard so there's so many things swirling
around um you know, of course about
Charlie Kirk's, you know, you know, who
he was as a person trying to defend him
and things like that. Um of things that
he said. Um, and people say, "Well," and
we, you know, said, "Well, um, when
somebody um,
like the church, we don't really hear
them speak out like not in leadership
roles or leadership in ministry roles
when uh, someone that doesn't look like
them or they think, well, using George
Floyd as an example, there was just like
crickets, you know, you could just hear
the crickets because there was even
though the whole world was talking, the
whole world was talking about it
>> and almost nothing I remember seeing um
Amish
>> women holding up signs, you know, just,
you know, saying what happened to George
Floyd was wrong. These are Amish people,
you know what I mean? Like literally,
but the Adventist church couldn't say
anything. So that was offensive to
people of color. I mean, so we kind of
like
>> that has been that what the things that
we've had to to deal with throughout I
know
>> for forever just kind of ignoring those
things. Um, but I've heard, you know,
people say, "Well, no. Um, you know, um,
Charlie Kirk and and George Floyd, they
weren't the same type of men." Meaning,
you know, George,
>> their names, their names should not be
mentioned in the same sentence,
>> but you know whose names Okay. So, I'm
like, "Okay, let's I mean, that's wrong.
That's completely I'm totally not in
agreement with that statement." But then
I just started thinking. I was like,
"Okay, well, I know this. They didn't
live at the same time, but let's use
Malcolm X."
>> Malcolm X. Okay. People try to say
Charlie Kirk was a a good husband and
according to his wife he was. I don't
have any reason to, you know,
>> think that that's not true. Malcolm X
was an excellent husband to Betty
Sheabz, his wife.
>> They had, you know, the deepest of love
relationship. He was also assassinated
in front of his wife and all of his
children. She was pregnant with the
twins. You know, I'm just saying like
and he and
not getting into conspiracy theory, but
Malcolm X actually even had a turning
point that they didn't mean that that's
not I didn't mean you know turning point
um
>> like because after he went to
>> Mecca and experienced you know I mean he
was a Muslim but he was worshiping Allah
you know a god to him um um with other
people of all different races. So he was
like, "You know what?
>> This is not just a black man's religion.
This is for everybody." But my point is
is Malcolm X was a good man.
>> You You definitely may have disagreed
with certain things, but he was a good
man. He was a good to his wife, good
father to his children.
>> Now, now watch this. Malcolm X
spoke a lot of negative things about
white people. He did before his
conversion after Mecca. He did. He got
changed. He changed.
>> When I became a Christian,
>> in my mind, I was like, man, if Malcolm
X was on his way to conversion and we
don't know the whole story, right?
>> You mean Charlie Kirk? Malcolm X. Oh,
Malcolm X. Okay. If he was on his way to
like maybe because remember Malcolm X
was actually introduced to Adventism as
a child.
>> They say um Yeah. His mom.
>> His mother. Yes. His mother was his
mother was that I think a literary
evangelist had come to her home and
given her the book. Like he recognized
he saw the book. He recognized like our
>> he was like there's no people. He's like
Adventists Seventh Day Adventists are
different from everybody else.
>> That's what he said. But anyway,
>> I think it was a white person who came
to murder.
>> As a Christian now,
>> I cannot, you know, say, yeah, Malcolm
X's hatred for white people at a certain
point in his life, you know, it was, you
know, hey,
I'm going to acknowledge,
okay, yeah, he his attitude towards
white people began to change,
>> right?
>> It definitely did.
>> So again,
yeah, that's right. Again,
I think the point is Charlie Kirk may
have been going through some changes. We
don't know. We cannot know
>> because we don't know what's in his
heart
>> right now.
>> It's one thing to hope for that. And I
think it's another thing to be willing
to say, hey, you know what? I appreciate
I appreciated Charlie Kirk for X, Y, and
Z, but I also at the same time
acknowledge that these were problematic.
At least that these were problematic,
>> right? And you may say, "Hey, I agree.
It's about context and all those things,
but I think the issue again is the
blanket. He was a hero."
>> So what what what black Adventists hear
now is, "Wait a minute.
Are you saying that all the stuff he
said you agree with?" So here's a
conversation. Here's a conversation,
right?
in the in your conversation, my black
friend uh and my white friend, my black
Adventist, my white Adventist uh uh
brother, sister, in the conversation, we
should be asking questions like,
"Help me to understand the context of,
you know, let's say uh the civil rights
movement was a was a mistake. help me to
understand
what context would make that statement
okay and then my white adventist friend
explain
it might be oh I get it now or it might
be that as you're trying to explain it
you're like what's coming out of my
mouth
>> right
>> wait a minute did I just say that
>> explain why explain why it's Christian
it's it would be all right for a
Christian to say that certain people,
even if they're talking about an
individual, don't have the brain power
to hold a particular office that belongs
that that should have gone to a white
person. There might be context
that says, "Hey, all right, that is a
Christian thing to say."
Explain it.
>> I don't
And and if you can't
>> I hate that comment. I hate that comment
the most because I'm a woman and black
and it's just so offensive.
>> But but explain it. In other words,
>> help us to understand why that's a
Christian thing to say,
>> right? why it's okay to to to say as a
Christian, like as a pastor, could I get
up and say, you know, that there are
certain people that don't have brain
power in our church, can I say
with those things that were said that
have been said, could I say those things
and still be considered Christlike?
>> Could I say those things and still be
considered uh a pastor who is preaching
the three angels messages? Mhm.
>> And and if I can't say those things and
be considered Christlike, then why is it
why are you giving a pass to someone
else to say these things
and then say that they're being that
they are Christlike, right? So again,
it's just being able to get down to the
root of the conversation and listen,
things can be taken out of context.
>> And I want to say yes. Yes, things can
be taken out of context. And I want to
say like, well, we're definitely not
making a blanket statement because like
you can meet a white Adventist friend
and they're going to be like, I totally
agree with you or I don't think that way
at all. You know what I'm saying? Like
that's
>> there's a lot of people out there like
that.
>> Yeah. Yeah. So, so again,
you ask the questions, right? And just,
you know, for those of you and again,
it's not white. There's some black
people who are like, "No, it wasn't
offensive." Okay, explain to me how
that's Christian. Explain to me. Help me
to understand. These are genuine
questions, right? Help me to understand.
>> Um,
and
how do I say this?
People can be taken out of context.
People take Ellen White out of context.
They will say Ellen White is a racist.
You know, we've had people say that
online. Ellen White's a racist.
>> And they've taken her statements out of
context. So, it is possible, right, to
take people's statements out of context.
>> You know, one thing that I love to do,
and I'm going to say, you know, go ahead
and try it yourself. Just go go online,
open up chat GPT,
and and just ask ChatGpt. Chad GBT,
gather all the evidence uh that you can
find and tell me, did Ellen White
say racist
things that were considered derogatory
to black people in her time
and you'll see chat GPT or if you know
you want to use Elon Musk's Grock and
just pull up Grock and say, "Hey, Grock
D." And it'll just spit out to you. Boom
boom boom boom boom boom boom. It's easy
to do that. A lot of these arguments
that you're hearing, you could just put
in, hey, did this person this are these
comments considered using your logic,
would these comments be considered
racist? You can even debate chat GPT.
What I'm saying is we we really do want
to do the research. Mhm.
>> We really want to see, okay, let's get
the context and let's see, would this be
considered
a racist statement in our day, in our
time,
>> right? So, for example, in Ellen White's
day, she had said that, you know, in
certain places, don't let uh uh don't
push for black people and white people
to integrate.
And people have taken that statement and
said see uh she is
she is a racist.
>> Mhm.
>> Failing to understand that the cont
context that she was speaking in was
listen they will burn the place down.
They will kill you Adventists and in the
south where they are the racism is so
deep and the prejudice is so deep that
we've got to move carefully.
>> Be wise.
>> Be wise. That's what she was saying.
Mhm.
>> People want to skip that context. Okay.
So, now I get it. I I get it now. What
you were saying was not racist.
Well, can you do the same thing for
these statements? Listen, it's not about
the man. Just take the statement. Leave
the man out of the picture and just take
the ideology, right? You know, I is it
true that uh is it is it racist to
>> I mean
>> is this idea something that should be
embraced by Christians by Adventists
that the civil rights movement was a
mistake
>> that um you know black people are more
prone uh to commit uh crimes? Mhm.
>> Are these things
objectively true
or are these statements that are being
made not realizing the context around
black history and black black history in
America?
>> Context is important. Context matters.
Have that discussion. Now, I want to
share something with you and then we're
going to close. We're going to we're
going to we'll close up with this. We're
not closing up yet, but I just want to
share something with you. And this is
for my white brothers and sisters,
right? I want you to understand
what confuses
uh black Adventists
as a whole. So, I'm going to show you a
couple of video clips and I'm going to
come back and explain to you in a
moment. Okay? And I want you to be aware
of this and then I'm going to make my
second appeal.
So
>> third,
>> no this be this be the first appeals
that we need to talk.
>> Okay.
>> So let's go let's go to the screen. I'm
going to show my first slide and I think
we need to pull up our earpieces.
>> Yes, we do
>> to hear. So I want to go ahead and and
uh play this this video clip. Hold on
before I do that. This gentleman's name
is Joel Webbin. um he is a Christian
nationalist
and he is uh speaking about the ten
commandments in this first clip. So, I
want you to listen. Watch
adopt a distinctly pre uh Christian
preamble and then all all the ten
commandments must be legislated. What
what we've done is we've thought the
second table of the law. So second table
meaning commandments 5-10 uh the
commandments of God that pertain to our
horizontal relationship with our
neighbor like don't steal, don't murder,
these kinds of things. We think that
should be legislated by the civil
magistrate, but the first table of the
law, not that. Um but that's not true.
And I'm not just talking about old
covenant Israel in the Old Testament.
You look at King Alfred, you look at
Constantine, uh you look at Richard the
Lionheart, uh you look at Duke Godfrey
who who chopped a a Turk uh in half
diagonally with one swing of the sword.
These guys, they legislated both tables
of the law. That's where all the
prosperity comes from. Uh because you
can't hang in midair uh these second
table commandments of don't steal from
your neighbor apart from uh have no
other gods before me. Idolatry is the
head, the fountain head of the stream.
You cannot have an idolatrous people and
yet somehow have a moral people.
Okay. So that's Joel Webbon, Christian
nationalist, and he's talking about how
the Ten Commandments need to be uh the
law of the land. Okay. And some of you
are familiar with this guy. You you're
putting some stuff in the chat. You
know, he's also believes that women
should should only stay at home and
other things like that. So here is here
is one of the faces of Christian
nationalism. Now I want you to watch
another clip by the same guy. Go ahead
and play this
pre uh Christian preamble and then all
all the ten commandments must be
legislated. What what we've done is we
thought the second table of the law
>> if you're a Christian white parent who
loves the Lord and loves your children
that you need to have the talk. The talk
that we're referencing is is the talk uh
that that takes your children according
to their maturity at the proper time,
the appropriate time and says uh there
are certain parts of town that you
cannot go and there are certain people
that you cannot be around.
>> Yep.
>> Right. Uh if there's someone who who is
black in our church and and they've been
in our church and we know them and they
love the Lord Jesus Christ, great. We're
not talking about that person, but we're
talking about when you go into a crowd
of people. If you go into a crowd of
strangers and they're white strangers,
there's some danger. If they're black
strangers, there is 30 times more
danger.
Them's the facts. And and it is actually
a failure of your parental duty. White
parents, please hear me. If you teach
your children growing up, if you lie to
them and say um all people and all races
of people in our country are the same,
they are not. You are actually depriving
your child of factual, truthful
information that could save their life.
Okay, I'm gonna I'm gonna address that
video in a second. And Sherry, no,
that's not a unpopular or that's not an
unpopular question. Yes, we I have, if
you saw what I said a little bit
earlier, Hebrew Israelites are racist
against white people. They believe all
white people are wicked, evil, and will
be lost.
um they don't have the same power
structure in which they can implement
any kind of harm, right? Keeping away
keeping them away from jobs or whatever.
So they don't have that kind of power.
>> They just all they can do is just hate
them in their hearts, right? And and say
in their own minds, one day when Jesus
comes again, he's going to allow all the
black people to rule over all the white
people. That's what they believe.
That's a pretty racist belief.
>> Okay. But they're not in a p they're not
in a position of authority, right, or
power in the government, in business
sectors. They're not in that any kind of
position to actually implement harm
on the people they're racist against.
And that's the difference. Okay. So,
this gentleman who was
>> somebody said that that gentleman was on
3ABM, but I don't believe that true.
>> Yeah, they they may have been talking
about Charlie Kirk. No, Charlie Kirk
wasn't on 3B.
>> He was he did an interview. Um he was
>> he while he was at
>> not on 3ABN.
>> No, not on.
>> Okay. So
this gentleman who is a Christian
nationalist and now you also see
is
now he doesn't say he's a racist. Mhm.
>> And that's the thing, you guys.
That's that really tricky soft racism
type of thing that I believe has become
popular
>> where you can be bold enough to say
something and then when people are like
shocked like what? You're like no no no
no no that that's not racist.
>> It's just I'm just stating an objective
fact.
And so there is this deniability
of I didn't say anything racist and if
you're offended,
>> it's really you, right? you're getting
worked up and you're getting So, this is
something that
that really
I don't want to use the word confuses
black people,
but it's definitely it definitely sounds
like
you're saying something very clearly
and then at the same time saying, "No,
no, no, not at all. I want you to watch
this next video." We got two more and
they're both like just I think one is
like a minute and then the other is just
a couple of about 25 seconds or so. So,
let's go to this next video. Same guy.
Same guy.
Here's the beauty of diversity. When it
comes to the kingdom of God and the
church of Christ, there's one thing, one
common denominator that all people from
every tribe, tongue, and language adore,
cherish, and love, and that's the gospel
of Jesus Christ. That's the word of God.
See, if you want to be an attractional
church, there's really nothing
ultimately wrong with that. The question
is just, who do you want to be
attractive to? I want to lead an
attractive church. I just want to be
attractive to the people of God. I want
to be attractive to Christians. Like 2
Corinthians chapter 2, I want to be a
lifegiving, attractive perfume spreading
the knowledge of the fragrance of Christ
everywhere to those who are being saved.
And the beauty is God's not a racist. He
is saving people from every tribe,
tongue, and language. So if I preach
Christ faithfully, all different kinds
of people will ultimately come.
Okay,
put a one in the chat if you're confused
right now.
Whether you're black or white, I just
want you to put a one in the chat if
you're confused right now.
If you're Mexican, whatever, whatever
you are, just go ahead and put a one in
the chat. If you're like,
is this the same guy we just heard
saying that
if you're black, if black people carry
30 times more danger than white people?
It's the same guy.
And so, some of you are saying, "Yeah,
I'm not confused." And and there and
here's what here's what I'm the point
I'm making, right?
is that to say something
and then to turn around and be like,
"Oh, no, no, that's not racist. It's
it's just true that
um you know,
more black people or black people as a
whole XYZ versus other
nation." No, no, no. That's not racism.
I'm a good guy. I'm a nice guy.
This is the problem, right? So, if it's
become popular to say hard truths, what
what many of us now seem to call
speaking the truth,
and
it is not of God.
be aware why some people as you're
talking may not may not hear what you're
saying,
>> right?
>> Go
>> it. I I'm only making clarif I'm just
clearing something up in the chat
because I so because there was still
some um
you know just some confusion still about
Charlie Kirk and 3. So I just want to
say that Charlie Kirk was invited to
it's something pearl was it was
>> wisdom pearl
>> wisdom pearls. Yeah it was just it was
so it's
>> and three men happened to be there so he
was not on
>> three was not there.
>> Danny Shelton was invited and his wife
was invited. There were many speakers
that were invited. These were Adventists
who put it on but it was not put on.
They were not a part of a conference.
Yeah. Um, I I have no I don't even know
if they're, you know, they're members of
a church, you know, I don't know that
part, but I do know that it was not
through a conference or anything like
that. It was not 3ABN, right? Danny
Shelton and his wife were actual guest,
right?
>> Um, and Charlie Kirk was a guest because
they, you know, heard that he kept the
Sabbath or whatever. So, they had him
talk about his Sabbathkeeping. So, I
just want to be very very very clear
that Charlie Kirk was never on 3ABN as a
guest of 3ABN, but it was this
>> nor nor is he a 7th Day Adventist.
>> No, he's not as some people have have
believed, you know, no have been told
that as well. So,
>> bottom line, you guys in all this, what
I'm saying is
>> we need to talk. Mhm.
>> And we have not said we have not said
Charlie Kirk is racist or Charlie Kirk
is not racist.
>> We haven't we've just said we need to
talk.
>> Get on the phone.
Have those conversations.
>> Explain why these statements should it
when when given in context
are Christian statements. statements
that are that that is okay for a
Christian to say or statements that are
not racist. Let's have the discussion,
right? And some people may end up
walking away saying, "No, he wasn't a
racist." And other people may walk away
saying he was. Everyone needs to be
convicted in their own minds. But the
thing we can't do
is be cold enough
>> to allow it to cause division in the
church.
>> We need to come together.
we need to talk.
>> So that brings me to my second um
my second and let me let me let me say
this very quickly. So someone asking
about stats. What about stats that say
that this is the case black people are
more out of the home than what about
those stats? So stats are cold numbers.
They don't give the story of what's
actually happening.
>> Do this. do this.
Um,
go to chat GPT and say, "Hey, this stat
says this about black people, black
black homes, black families, crime rate,
whatever.
Does this stat tell the whole picture of
why this is so?
Some people say this stat means x, y,
and z."
>> Analyze this statement for me.
and
and give me your response and you'll be
shocked guys. You know, we talk about,
you know, studying to show yourself
approved.
>> It it's one thing to it's one thing to
uh to hear something and just start
repeating it, but it's another thing to
actually like check it out from all
different angles. Mhm.
>> And some people may be like, you know,
go online. Go online and do this and
don't look up the sources that you
think, you know, are going to back up
what you say, right? Stats don't tells
the story.
>> They may show that black people get
arrested more often than white people,
but it doesn't doesn't show
the overpolicing. It doesn't show why
that's going on. So when we just look at
stats as cold hard facts and say this is
the truth that De them's the facts we
have an issue
>> right
>> we have an issue so again we need to
have those discussions and I'm telling
you some of us will see
>> are going to see that we have some
hidden things in the heart that we
didn't know were there
>> biases
>> hey you're right
>> I'm calling this divisive but I'm
calling that bold and you know uh
reformer-like and and and this is God's
boldness on these individuals but this
individual is being divisive this
individual is being angry why do we do
that how are we being double how are we
how are we manipulating or how are we
being selectively
empathetic
>> I'm g say one more thing I forgot to
this. So, I'm going to go back to the
George Floyd thing,
>> okay?
>> When when when black people are now told
that even having empathy
about what happened to George Floyd
means that you're a Marxist who wants to
see families destroyed
because you think that black lives
should matter. And then that statement
is taken BLM
>> Marxist organization witchcraft that is
ab it's just like wait what? So because
I believe that black lives are important
I support Marxist ideology.
>> We got to have the talk.
>> So this brings me to my second
>> appeal
which is this.
I think I think
that
this may be crazy, but I think
that we could really use a 10day
gathering. I think the general
conference
>> Oh, wow.
>> Yeah.
>> You think anything you haven't passed by
me first, you might be you might say
crazy.
>> I think we need to just have a 10day
>> Wow.
meeting, not a GC conference, a 10-day
conference, a five-day conference,
something where we come together for the
specific purpose
of fulfilling Matthew chapter 5.
Coming together
>> to talk about how things why things so
easily divide us. Why did the COVID
vaccination thing cause so much
division? Why is this Why did the George
Floyd thing Why is this thing How is it
that we are becoming so easily
divided against one another?
>> We need to come together just like the
disciples did on the day of Pentecost.
We need to come together to look each
other in the eye
and pray with one another and talk about
how is it that we can begin to even
disagree on a thing and still embrace
one another as brother and sister.
I think that's why the regional
conferences statement
>> is so powerful
>> because
and again I always go to this but this
is what I teach in in therapy with
couples like or even you know with
individuals like you don't want to
suppress
these negative emotions and never deal
with it or talk about it and that is
what we have done
and not just in Adventism but the world
does that too but I'm just saying,
"Well, no, the world kind of just talks
about stuff, but and gets it out there,
but but within the church, we just have
never had a conversation. We have just
coexisted,
had hurt feelings, had our own thoughts
and and feelings about things, but never
discussed it with each other. um or
never even shared like, hey, this is
actually offensive to us or we feel like
this is discrimination towards us. Like
again, we talk about that amongst each
other,
>> but we've never
>> Yeah.
>> discussed it. Um and then the other
sides are like, "Okay, well, you're just
fine with it, so I'm going to keep on
doing it because you're not saying
anything." No, I think what them putting
out that letter, some people thought
that was divisive. No, that is like
healthy and healing because the letter
was written, you know, I've read it
thoroughly. There were no mean-hearted
statements in there. There was no unkind
statements in there. It was like this is
what the Bible says. This is what we
feel. We need to have dialogue
>> to talk.
>> That's that's healthy.
>> That is healthy. Ignoring things is not
healthy. Not in your individual life.
>> Yeah.
>> Yeah. So,
>> not as a denomination. So appeal one,
start talking to each other,
>> but it's the way you talk.
>> Get on the phone.
>> Go in that private chat. Start talking
to each other. And appeal number two, I
can't do it. You know, I mean, I I am
not anybody significant in the general
conference.
>> Well, yeah.
>> Or even the NAD. Even the NAD. I think
that we need a time to come together and
all those issues uh uh all those issues
that have that have been causing
division. We got to ask ourselves how is
it that the devil is able
to drop these things in our midst and we
just
go to war.
And re well I mean this is a statement I
just want to say I mean really okay well
really conversion needs to h I mean if
you're converted you're going to love
all people
>> that's the bottom line you guys
>> you're going to love all people
>> that is the bottom line my message last
week about seeing people as the enemy
>> it is the it is the it is the bottom
line problem when we start demon
demonizing
groups of people.
When we start demonizing, yeah, they're
after this and they're after that and
they're do and they're doing this and
the the you know, this organization is
trying to do this.
>> Once we get in that mindset, you guys,
>> it's the devil's fielding.
>> I don't have a lot to say. I I I mean, I
just I I don't know. Yeah. If you when
you're converted, when you're truly
converted, you love all people. And if
you because I've heard I'm sorry, guys,
I have to say this. I've heard people
say, you know, and for what Charlie
believed, he should have never lost his
life.
>> Yeah.
>> That that's just I can't say that
enough. He should have never lost his
life. Um he is a human being. He's a
father. He's a um a husband, a son. He's
he's a human being, period.
But there's people who have made him
turned him I don't think he called
himself this. I don't know maybe he did.
I don't think he did but you know an
evangelist. And I'm just like so an
evangelist for the gospel and for Jesus
didn't focus so much on
one race and what they're doing and you
know you know what I'm saying like the
gospel of Jesus is that's not it. The
focus should be on Jesus and that we are
all in the same boat. We are all sinners
and we all need Jesus and win people to
Christ.
>> Yeah.
>> Period.
>> Because I think just the focus um of it
was
honestly I'll just be honest and
transparent. I just don't understand. I
really don't understand the focus if
you're winning people to Jesus. I don't
understand focusing on
one group of people and supposedly their
issues and problems.
>> And I don't see how that's not very
obvious to some people. Yeah.
>> Who claim to be Christians.
>> Yeah.
>> This is a search your
>> That's my point of view.
>> Yeah.
>> Not saying that's LMLC's point of view.
>> Yeah. This is a search your heart
moment, you guys. It's a search your
heart moment. And um you know I think
it's unfortunate that even after this I
think people are so looking for an enemy
that despite a call to communicate
despite a call to you know let's come
together despite a call to we've got to
address this and then and move forward
like people will still be like
yep Here goes more apostasy in the
church
>> and it's a sad sad thing
>> but it is what it is.
>> Yeah,
>> we didn't discuss what you said when
about the coming together. That would be
great. I think it would be great to have
that conversation. It needs to happen.
But unfortunately,
I mean,
the Bible is true and there is a
shaking. And we think the shaking is
just about doctrinal doctrinal things.
>> There is a shaking.
>> It will happen.
>> But
>> but I think the conversation is needed
for sure.
>> Yeah.
>> Individually.
And it would be nice to just come come
together and have, you know, for that
purpose. But like,
>> yeah,
>> guys, we all claim we love Jesus.
>> Yeah.
>> And we love this truth.
>> Yeah. It cannot
>> And we want to get the gospel to the
world.
>> Yeah.
>> So, we're going to have to come together
and talk.
>> It cannot hurt to come together to pray
together.
>> Yes.
>> To fellowship together.
>> Somebody mentioned fasting. Pray and
fast
>> and not have sermons about what position
is right. and what position is wrong,
>> right?
>> But talk about,
>> you know, have those those those,
you know, workshop meetings where we're
able to dialogue and discuss and
>> and above all to have those messages
focused on why we need to be unified on
the preaching of the third angel's
message,
>> right? and and our mission and how the
devil is sidetracking us
>> and how we can how we can have each
other's back.
>> Anyway, that is it y'all.
>> Yeah, that was extended,
>> but we're going to try to
>> trim some trim some time. Well, anyways,
that was I'm glad you said extended
because we definitely did extend, but
we'll try to make up some time in some
other places.
>> Yep. I sound like those pilots who are
like gonna get you to your destination.
Wait, we'll make up time in the air.
>> Yeah.
>> Yes. But hopefully this was um this was
just the beginning of We don't know
who's watching, honestly. We don't know
if it's if we're preaching to the choir,
if you will. But um just share this.
Share this and have that conversation.
>> Yeah.
>> And we're going to end in prayer.
>> All right. We're going to end in prayer.
So,
>> but stay with us. We're not going
anywhere. This is still church. So do
not don't don't tune out. Stay with us
because you're
>> the the the message today will be um an
American crisis Christianity at a
crossroads.
>> Yes.
>> And uh we're going to talk about what
what it means to be a Christian.
>> Amen.
>> All right.
>> You want to pray?
>> Okay. Heavenly Father, Lord, we just
want to thank you for this time to come
together um Lord and just to begin to
have um just to discuss some of the of
the things that we don't normally um
talk about um and Lord um we just do it
amongst each other and not um from this
type of platform, Lord. So, I just thank
you for this time again together uh with
everyone. And I just pray that the
things that were shared will um just
start um to think about things in a
different way and to pray about them,
Lord, and um to just to decide to have
that conversation with somebody who
doesn't look like you, think like you,
Lord, and to just have that open
dialogue. And we ask these things in
Jesus name. Amen.
>> Amen.
Southeast Asia is my favorite travel
destination on earth. And one of my
favorite places here in Southeast Asia
is an intriguing Indonesian island
potent with personality and
vibrant in culture. A place where
beautiful lessons for life. Come and
explore with me the beauty of Bali
inside and out.
[Music]
This is an amazing entrance right here.
Check it out.
Adventurers, explorers, photographers,
and surfers. Divers, hikers, bikers, and
backpackers, families, honeymooners, and
solo travelers, Bali has something for
everyone. The climate is warm and humid
year round. Endless summers with average
highs in the 80s. It seems like Bali has
it all. Pristine beaches, lush
landscapes, steaming jungles, cascading
waterfalls, abundant fields, towering
volcanoes, singing streams, stunning
cliffs, powerful waves, delicious food,
captivating artwork, rich cultural
festivities, intriguing religious
ceremonies, and that unmistakable
laid-back way of life, and some of the
best diving in the world. The
breathtaking island of beauty is a
dreamy destination.
Due to the small and congested roads,
the best way to get around this island
is by motorbike. This is how the locals
do it. The benefit of the bike is that
you can get around traffic much more
quickly and efficiently. But the
drawback is that you're now exposed to
all the nasty elements of the outside.
Not only the dust and the dirt, but also
the vehicle exhaust, pollution, stinky
sewers, and other foul scents you can
imagine. Though Bali is pristine,
tragically, it's also polluted with
plastics. But one thing I notice about
my time spent here in Bali is that
despite the stinky sense of everyday
life, the smell of the atmosphere is
mostly sweet and fragrant. And this is
true everywhere you go. Bali is an
aromatic oasis where the nose is not
neglected and breathing is a blessing.
But what is the source of the sweet
aroma therapy in the atmosphere? It
actually comes straight from the heart
of the Balines people who are so devoted
in their daily offerings. Every day,
usually in the mornings and evenings,
cultural and religious offerings are
placed at the entrances of every home
and every business and pretty much
everywhere you go. These fragrant
offerings consist of rice, flowers,
fruits, spices, and burning incense
placed in a tiny handwoven basket made
from leaves. These offerings can be
spotted in every crack and corner of
this island. As the incense rises, so
does my gratitude for the sweet sense of
life. Every day, the fragrance of Bali
is always sweet and pleasant. The aroma
of the atmosphere in Bali reminds me of
the realities of life living in this
broken world. Not everything in life is
foul, and not everything in life is
fragrant. Life is usually made up of a
mixture of both. fragrant experiences of
joy and laughter, but also the foul
experiences of sadness and sorrow, the
pleasant aroma of love and truth, but
also the nauseating odor of injustice
and selfishness. You see, it doesn't
matter who you are, you cannot escape
the various scents of your surroundings.
Both the sweet and the sour smells of
life affects everyone who breathe in its
atmosphere. Such is the case with the
highs and lows of life and death, the
valleys and the mountaintops of tragedy
and triumph, the light and the darkness
of failure and success. Life is made up
of both. The tasty aroma of delicious
food, but also the foul smells of
rubbish and waste. Now, there are two
ways we can respond to this reality of
life. We can either complain about the
stench or we can appreciate the sweet.
We can gripe about our problems or we
can count our blessings with gratitude
if it wasn't for the presence of the
stench. Many would not fully appreciate
the fragrance of the sweet. It's going
through the hard times that makes us
more appreciative of the easy times. And
so let us learn from the unpleasantries
of life. We cannot ignore the reality
that many times life stinks. And
although most of the time we can't
change our stinky circumstances, there
is something we can do to make it
better. Just like the people of Bali, we
can light up the incense of prayer.
Prayer that rises to the heavens. Now,
prayer may not remove the stench or
change the circumstance, but rather it
gives us the ability to see it and smell
it differently. Prayer helps us overcome
stinking thinking. And it gives us a
positive perception to every foul and
fragrant experience of life, both the
smelly and the sweet. But besides the
incense of prayer, just like the
Balines, every day we can present a
sweet smelling life offering of love,
humility, and gratitude. For when we
learn to live in love, give in humility,
and be grateful in simplicity, our lives
become a sweet fragrance in a foul world
of pain and sorrow. We can be the answer
to our own prayer. Our positive
perception to all the various sense of
life can permeate the atmosphere and
inspire those around us. This is the
experience I've had with the beautiful
people of this place. The Balines are
some of the friendliest and sweetest
people on earth. Their daily offerings
are a reflection of the sweetness of
their love. Their history, culture, art,
and influence are things to appreciate
and celebrate. Their smiles and their
kindness are things to emulate. So come
if you can, but always remember to love
where you are. Open your mind and your
heart to those around you, both
strangers and friends. Listen in order
to learn and do so with empathy and
non-judgmental ears. And let everything
you do be done with love. For this is
the sweet fragrance of Bali. It is the
sweet smell of love. Today, may your
life be the offering and may love be the
fragrance that makes the offering known,
felt, and even smelt wherever you go.
[Music]
What other lessons can we learn from the
beautiful island of Bali? Please share
in the comments below. And when you have
a minute, please check out the rest of
our episodes shot all over the world.
Each is unique and special. A perfect
dose of captivation, exploration, and
inspiration for your day. See more
episodes and partner with us at the
website below. Your monthly pledge will
empower us to continue creating
life-changing content for all. If you'd
like to join me on an epic excursion in
Hawaii, or create some meaningful
artistic imagery, or perhaps vibe to the
musings of some meaningful
conversations, or see more of my
incredible views of nature and life,
check out my other websites here. And of
course, please connect with us on
YouTube, Instagram, and Facebook. Thank
you for your precious time, attention,
and support. Aloha always. Mahalo and
Marinata.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Heat. Heat.
Heat.
[Music]
Welcome back, Living Mana Church family.
So glad you decided to continue to
worship with us today. If you are just
joining us for the first time, please
put in the chat where you're watching
from. Let us know if this is your first
time by putting a one and where you're
watching from. We want to say a special
welcome to you and again we just love to
see where everybody is viewing from. We
are an international church so we know
we had somebody earlier from Perth,
Australia and different parts of Europe
and even South Africa and then all
around the United States. Please let us
know uh who is here now. I want to know
if you're just joining us for the divine
worship service. Want to say a very uh
special welcome to you if this is your
very first time. So, please put a one in
the chat. And again, we're just thankful
that you are here and wanting to worship
with us here on this Sabbath day. So,
all right, we have Jerry from San Diego.
Welcome, Jerry. Always good to see you
here. We have Sharon from Maryland.
Mariah from Phoenix, Arizona. Good to
see you. Tiffany Britt, so good to see
you on here as always. But um Ringold,
Georgia. Good to see you here, Tiffany.
Um let's see. We have Clint from Long
View, Texas. Our very own Clint, our our
number one viewer for Mental Health
Mondays. It's always good to see you,
Clint. Uh here. Um and Daniel is from
Houston, Texas. Good to see you here. Uh
Karen from um the Caribbean. Good to see
you. Uh, Christina from ReppingP,
Arizona. Good to see you here. Warren
from Warren, New York. All right. You
You live in a place that has your name.
That's cool. All right. Jea from
Florida. Good to see you, Sister Shaine.
Um, Tom Joyce Fiser from Canada. Good to
see you here. We have Jimmy from
Whitmore Lake, Michigan. Good to see you
here. Beverly from Minnesota.
All right. Nurse Andy from Missouri.
Good to see you. Erica from Bermuda.
Karen from Jamaica. Mooney from Toronto,
Canada. Welcome here to Living Mana
Church. So glad to see each and every
one of you. And again, if this is your
very first time, please put a one in the
chat. Want to say a special welcome to
you and our viewers and our membership.
Definitely want to to greet you. Want to
let you guys know how you can stay
connected to Living Mana Church. The
best way to do that if you are in North
America is you're going to want to get
text alerts. And you can sign up to get
those by texting LMC to the 855 number
that you see there on your screen.
That's going to be the best way for you
to get reminders of programming when we
uh go live. Like this week we had our
first Mental Health Monday back for
season 4 with myself and Dr. Ricardo
White. Uh so that was exciting. Um, and
then we also had True Health Tuesdays on
a Tuesday with Dr. Maria uh Hume. And so
that is it's people were reminded like,
hey, we're on on Monday and Tuesday. We
have programming on Wednesdays and we
will have be having programs on
Thursdays again. So you want to be
reminded. You're not you're thinking
like, "Hey, I want to I want to check
that out." But during the week, you
you're probably going to forget. So
those text alerts definitely are very
very helpful at helping you stay
connected. If you're not in America, if
you're not in North America, you're not
going to be able to do the text alerts.
And so as you can see, many of you are
from all around the world, but you can
get all of this information on Mighty
Networks. So whether you're in North
America or if you're international,
you're still going to want to sign up
for Mighty Networks because it is our
virtual church home. that is uh where
you're going to learn about our small
groups, get information about um
announcements and upcoming events. And
so you're going to want to sign up for
Mighty Networks and you can do that.
There's a there's a um there's a link in
the chat and you will be able to sign up
for Mighty Networks. And so again,
that's our virtual church home.
Everything that we do here on Living
Mana is there in Mighty Network. So,
you're going to want to get sign up for
that so you can get all of that
information. Want to also remind you
guys that we do have children's
programming LOC kids. So, if you would
like to get your kids involved in LMOC
kids, you can text kids to that 855
number. You can also email, send an
email there that you see LMOC kids at
living mana.urch.
and LMLC kids starts at 11:30 central
time and they go for about an hour and a
half. So if you want to get your kids
involved, definitely text kids to the
855 number or send an email to that
email that you see there on the screen.
We also believe in prayer here at Living
Mana Church. We have a prayer team. We
are big on prayer here at Living Mana
Church. And so if you have prayer
requests and you would like the our
prayer team to pray for you, please send
an email to praymanana.urch.
If you join mighty networks, you can
also send you can also put your prayer
request on the prayer wall and our team
gathers those requests and you can also
text pray to that 855 number and you
will be able to send your prayer request
in that way. Our prayer team does not
stop praying for your request until you
send back and let us know that you know
God has answered this prayer and um and
if you're okay with it. many prayer
requests, I mean many prayer answers to
prayers testimonies will will be shared
with uh sister Amara during our prayer
time and so you can send in an answer to
your prayers that way as well. We also
have the power line. The power line is
something new in addition to what we do
on power with power Wednesdays. We have
power Wednesdays a program, but the
power line is also on Wednesdays and
that's at 8:00 PM central. And that that
that is just prayer. Like it's live
prayer. If you come to the power line,
you bring your prayer request, put it in
the chat, and the prayer team right
there live on air is going to pray over
your prayer request. And so it's great
for you to share the power line with
your friends, uh your your family, your
co-workers, whoever, anybody you know
that's going through something. You can
say, "Hey, I'm going to take this to my
church on the power line and they're
going to pray on for it today." or you
could come with me. Just put your prayer
request in there and you will hear them
praying over your prayer request live.
So, it's a great way to share um our
prayer ministry here at Living Mana
Church. Also just want you uh to know
that we are going to be having communion
and that communion is October 31st and
you can scan that QR code to get more
information where you can and you're
scanning for supplies. So where you can
get communion bread, get the communion
juice and also get the uh recipe if
you'd like to make your own communion
bread. So that's going to be October
31st at 700 p.m. Central time. That will
be a communion.
Also, just want to thank you guys for
being so just listening to God um spirit
and speaking to you and been so faithful
in giving. you've been so faithful for
the last three and a half years that um
living mana church has has has been when
we started and you guys have been so
good and faithful in giving and
supporting the church and we just want
to say thank you for that. If you want
to continue to give you can go to
adventistgiving.org.
There you will see you put in living
mana church and you will see a virtual
tithe envelope. There you can give your
tithe. your tithe um goes to support the
Northeastern Conference and the
worldwide 7th Day Adventist Church where
you see local church um budget there
that helps to um support what we're
doing here with Living Mana Church. So,
all of the things that you see, or maybe
you don't see, but all you know, we have
because I'm broadcasting live to you
now, the cameras, the lights, the all
the equipment that it takes to be able
to go live and all of the different
things that we support here at to make
all of this happen for Living Mana
Church. That comes from that fund when
you give to the local uh church budget.
But you will also see a line there for
the benevolence fund where we're able to
help those who are requesting in need of
assistance. We're able to do that and we
take that from the benevolence fund and
there are other areas and categories to
give on that tithe envelope as well. So,
that's the one way that you can give
virtually to continue to support Living
Mana Church online, but you can also uh
mail in um a pay a what you're wanting
to give your tithe and offering to
Living Mana Church by following uh that
address there that you see on your
screen, the PO Box 428, Owens
Crossroads, Alabama 35763.
So, those are the two ways that you can
give um if you're give to Living Mana
Church. And again, we just want to say
thank you because you guys have been so
uh faithful in supporting this church,
not just financially, but through your
prayers, by showing up each week, by
sharing uh this link and the messages
and talking about it with people. We
really do appreciate it. That is why um
the within this in the next year in 2026
we'll be um celebrating our fourth year.
So and that's because of your commitment
and your dedication um and just praying
for the church financially supporting
the church uh but just um just coming
just sharing to with people who we are
and the messages that are coming from
living mana church. So again we just
want to say thank you. want to invite
you at this time to pray with me uh as
we give a prayer of thanksgiving to God.
So, if you please just bow your heads
with me as we pray.
Heavenly Father, Lord, want to thank you
for this Sabbath, Lord. Want to thank
you for uh even our Sabbath school and
the conversation we were able to have.
Uh Lord, talking about things that we
don't always talk about. Um but really
encouraging all of us to have more
needed conversations in a loving and
respectful way. Lord, I just want to
lift up everyone that is viewing um this
broadcast, whether it's live or um after
we are live. Lord, I want to lift up all
of the needs of those who are viewing,
Lord. And there's so many things that we
go through. We go through health issues,
financial issues, family issues, marital
issues. Lord, there's so many things
that we go through on this earth, Lord,
and I just want to lift all of them up
to you. So for those who are hurting for
whatever reason, Lord, for whatever
category they fall in, Lord, I pray that
you will send peace to them, that they
that they will feel your presence in
their life, Lord, even when they're
going through those things. if they are
on their sick bed, Lord, that you would
heal them, that that you would send
peace, that they would know that you are
with them even during this time while
they are sick and they can have hope and
your healing power, Lord. Lord, I pray
for all the families. I pray for all the
marriages, the things that need to take
place, the apologies, the change of
hearts, the change of character, Lord,
the things that need to happen to make
the the the home, the family, the
marriage a happy place. Lord, I just
pray that that will happen. Lord, I want
to lift up Pastor Meyers. Ask that you
would speak through him that you would
that whatever you have given him to
share with all of us that he will say it
in such a way that it will touch our
hearts and it will change our hearts,
Lord, and change who we are. That we
will walk away different and changed um
than the way that we came in. And Lord,
we just thank you again for this Sabbath
day and just pray for all your many
blessings in Jesus name. Amen.
[Music]
[Applause]
8.2 billion people. Each one unique.
Each one unlike the next. All living on
a tiny rock suspended in space, drifting
through an everex expanding universe.
8.2 billion people, barely a speck in
the vastness of creation.
And yet, every single one is deeply
loved by the very God who made it all.
[Music]
But this isn't just any love.
It's a love that transforms.
A love that defeats death and reshapes
eternity.
A love that reconciles and restores.
A love that reconnects the creation to
its creator.
For God so loved the world
that he gave his only son that whoever
believes in him shall not perish but
have eternal life.
Why would God do such a thing?
He had 8.2 billion reasons.
[Music]
I need you.
You need me.
We're all a part of God's body.
Stand with me.
Agree with me. We're all a part of God's
body.
It is his will that every need be
supplied.
You are important
to me. I need you to survive.
I need you.
You need me.
We're all a part of God's body.
Stand with me.
Agree with me. We're all a part of God's
body.
It is his will that every need be
supplied.
You are important
to me. I need you to survive.
[Music]
I pray for you. You pray for me. I love
you. I need you to survive. I won't harm
you with words from my mouth. I love
you. I need you to survive. I pray for
you. You pray for me. I love you. I need
you to survive. I won't harm you with
words from my mouth. I love you. I need
you to survive. I pray for you. You pray
for me. I love you. I need you to
survive. I won't harm you with words
from my mouth. I love you. I need you to
survive. I pray for you. You pray for
me. I love you. I need you to survive. I
won't harm you with words from my mouth.
I love you. I need you to survive. I
pray for you. You pray for me. I love
you. I need you to survive. I won't harm
you with words from my mouth. I love
you. I need you to survive. It is his
will that every need be supplied.
You are important to me. I need you to
survive.
[Music]
Here at Living Mana, we bear each
other's burdens. When you need support
or prayer, when you're feeling
discouraged
or alone or anxious,
you don't have to face life struggles
alone.
[Music]
Let us come boldly unto the throne of
grace that we may obtain mercy and find
grace to help in our time of need.
The Lord is close to the brokenhearted
and saves those who are crushed in
spirit.
[Music]
Amen. Amen. Praise the Lord. Greetings,
saints of the most high God. So good to
be here once again with you, worshiping
here at Living Man Online Church. As
always, I'm here with my lovely bride,
Amra, and we are certainly thankful
thankful to be alive today and to be
able to call on the name of the Lord one
more time. So, how's everybody doing?
How was your week? How are you making
it? How you coming through? Thank God
for being a God who answers prayer. Uh,
you know, um, wow, a lot a lot to think
about, a lot to pray about, a lot to
talk about. So, we know, uh, you're
definitely going to be on your knees
praying this week. Want to do some shout
outs here. Of course. Um I was thinking
a lot about Sister Ashante Tucker. If
you're watching, want to thank you for
always gathering all of the prayer
requests from uh Messenger and send them
over to us here uh at the prayer team.
Want to thank uh Sister Sheilaard. Thank
you for all your beautiful work that you
do. Still want to get together, have a
chat with you after you got back from
the women's conference, you and Sister
Denise. Sister Denise shared a powerful
testimony of how the Lord healed her leg
and and I'm sure you got some wonderful
stories to share with us. So looking
forward to getting together with you.
Had a wonderful conversation on the
phone with our girl today. I hope you're
watching Sister Charlotte
there in Texas. Everybody loves you here
at Living Mana. Your encouragement to
us. Sister Charlotte such a soldier. I
mean going through it and she still has
an encouraging spirit. Always
encouraging to us.
>> I have some praise reports from her.
Amen. Well, that's wonderful and it was
good to be able to uh chat with you. I
mean, she's been going through one thing
after the next, but she continues to be
a witness even in the middle of her
storm. Amen.
>> She's in the hospital over there in
Texas. Um
>> she's in Flower Mound, Texas. Flower
Mount, Texas. And even in her her room,
she's been able to be a witness to a
tech. One of the texts came in named
Diamond and found out that she was a
Sabbathkeeper and Charlotte was right
there. You're just taking my praise
report right from my
>> Well, there it is. Sorry about that.
>> I'm I'm still going to read it.
>> All right. I got the inside scoop on
that, Charlotte. Sorry to get ahead of
myself there, but we can't help but tell
all the good things God has done. So,
um,
>> hello Shereice Henley.
>> Oh, yes, we have I think.
>> Hi, Clint.
>> Okay.
>> Hello, Pauline. Hello, blessing.
Thank you so much for
>> Here's a roll call. Just jump right in
the middle of my shout out. Sorry,
continue with your shout outs, but I had
to.
>> We will. Ashley and John in South
Carolina, we are shouting you out today.
Love y'all and good to see you. Brother
Reed, we've got a powerful praise report
from you and looking forward to hearing
that. Christina and Pauline, y'all do a
wonderful job of gathering all of the
prayer requests from the chats and just
putting them together and getting them
out to all of the prayer warriors. So,
we're thankful for y'all and the
beautiful work that you do.
Um, I actually today have um a praise
report myself. Some of you may have
heard I I'm just going to praise God for
CO. I got CO.
>> He has CO and he's still here.
>> Yeah. But you know what God did? God
used CO to uh sit Brother Terry down
>> and get some rest.
>> And get some rest. And uh I realized
that's what it was. And so he'd been
talking to us uh for the last couple of
weeks, months maybe that um sometimes we
pray for the storm to go away. We want
the storm gone. We want the happy
ending. We want the problems gone. Of
course, we want the pain and the
sickness gone. But sometimes, you know,
it's all about God's purpose. And God
will use those things to change us. And
then when we are changed, then those
things are no longer needed. And so, for
example, I, you know, I really
appreciate the Sabbath school today. And
I know a lot of you did. I saw you. You
appreciate the Sabbath school
conversation. And yes, uh what an
awesome appeal by our pastor. I love our
pastor and the approach that God gives
him to things. We want to stay true to
principle and that's what we're looking
at, the principles. Um so we were we're
praying that we'll be able to have those
loving uh conversations uh which uh
>> tend to be uncomfortable conversations,
but hey, you know what? Uh, like we saw
in Taj's video, the world has both sweet
fragrances and not so sweet fragrances.
And because of Jesus, we can take all of
that and cause it to work together for
good. You know, as long as God's leading
the way. Um, I wanted to say something.
I I needed to say this because when I
studied the classical writings of a
Christian who died in communist China in
1927, his name was Watchman Knee. He
wrote a book in three volumes called
Spiritual Man. And one of the things I
found in that book, he said that
Christians, modern Christians are like
murky ponds.
>> You know, uh, our surface is glossy and
glassy and it looks so beautiful until
someone disturbs our surface and then
all that muck and mire from the bottom
will rise up.
>> We don't want to be murky ponds
Christians. We don't want our
Sabbathkeeping and our vegetarianism and
our right doctrine and all that stuff
>> to come turn out to be a curse to the
world. We want to be a blessing. That's
the covenant that God gave to Abraham. I
want to bless you, make your name great,
and make you a blessing. And we're seed
of we're Christ, and we're the seed of
Abraham, heirs according to the promise.
So, we're to be a blessing. And so, I'm
praying that church, that's what we'll
do. We'll hear the voice of God as he's
speaking through his man's servant and
our first lady that we will come and
we'll have loving conversation, be true
Christians. Let's be true Christians.
Let's be true Seventh Day Adventists. It
broke my heart. You know, our pastor is
such a researcher, but doesn't it break
your heart to look back in history and
see Adventist slinging a machete at
another Adventist, another human being,
but another Adventist um to see what
happened with the Nazi party people in
the name of Christ. So, could be so
deceived. And so, let's remain true to
principle. Let's stay at the foot of the
cross. Let's stay with our eyes and on
Jesus, our mind on Jesus, and our heart
fixed. and don't let this enemy deceive
our hearts and mind. God, don't let the
enemy defeat your people's mind. That's
my prayer today in Jesus name.
>> Amen.
>> And so, love y'all. Love y'all. And I'm
also praying that we will get a
revelation of that beautiful song we
just heard. I need you to survive. You
have to have a revelation of the body of
Christ in order to sing along with that
from the heart. I need you. You need me.
And uh you know, look at Amra. Here's a
praise report. Amra. Not only did Amra
overcome, I mean, she she she's married
a brother, right? But she married a
brother from the other side of the
track, so she overcame all that stuff.
Jesus will come in and fix it, won't he?
>> Look, I put this in the chat earlier. I
find it a true privilege and it's an
honor to be able to have hard
conversations
and to have such a diverse community
around me to be married into a black
family who I absolutely love and adore.
>> I have never let anyone's backgrounds
um detour me from having a better
knowledge of others.
>> Yeah.
>> Amen. So, praise God. Uh anyway, I thank
God for uh these troubling times and
these troublesome conversations. And I I
thank God for it because what it's doing
is it's allowing us to grow. It's
allowing us to be healed. It's allowing
us to search our own hearts like pastor
said and and and you know, sometimes
we're surprised by some of the things
that come up out of our own mouth. You
know, I imagine Peter when he was
standing by the fire and cursed and
denied Christ, you know, he probably
thought, "Where'd that come from?" Well,
it didn't come from nowhere. It was
there.
>> Yeah.
>> So, praise God. And but but we together
we'll get through. Amen. Brother Clint,
I see you there in the chat. He sat you
down, too. Hey, some of us have to be
sat down, bro. I thought I'd had enough
of that after 25 years, but came out and
then the storms came and then I thought,
well, you know, I'm going to be just
running and working and working overtime
and doing so much. But you know what? Uh
the the the prayer team reminded me this
morning of a song. All of my help cometh
from the Lord. Amen. And and and not
from me or anywhere else. anything else
that we could do. God is still good,
y'all. He's still good. He's still
working miracles. He's still on the
throne. We can believe in him and trust
in his ways.
>> You know, I praise God that I don't I
didn't get CO from you. I'm still
testing negative probably because I've
been on antibiotics like on and off for
the last nine months.
>> But, uh,
>> yes, I'm I'm glad you're not getting it,
too. That's
>> I see people in the chat. Um, thank you
so much for your prayers. Laya, Shaunin,
Smegali, have a wonderful night and a
sweet sleep.
>> Amen.
>> Um, yeah, so many people have been
praying for us. Thank you so much. You
know, um,
>> beautiful prayers. Sister Matina, thank
you for your consistent encouragement
always. Brother Kashie, uh, the, uh,
Brother Elco and the men's group,
Brother Ross and Sister Gina, just
beautiful. Everybody's beautiful. We
love y'all. Nicole, I see you there. I
don't want to leave anybody out, but
y'all
>> Renee Thomas is giving us a shout out
from San Jose, California, where we
>> All right.
>> just moved from three years ago. We're
only about an hour and a half away and
we come there often to visit. So,
>> Amen.
>> Yeah. Amen.
>> Awesome.
>> So, anyway, again, be encouraged,
saints. Uh God is God is still in
charge. I've got to mention one more.
Sister Karen
shared a testimony this past Wednesday
at Power Wednesday and everybody's
sitting there and I know everybody's
like, "Okay, when we gonna get to the
end when Jesus just kicks the door in
and rescues her and saves her and
everything's and it didn't happen that
way, but she continued to praise and
trust God with such conviction and joy
and and you could hear it in her." And
it's that way with Sister Karen all the
time, you know, and uh I love Sister
Karen, you know, when she's praising
God. She's got that heavy Jamaican
accent, you know, and I just love my
sister Karen. But Sister Karen prays
reports like that are such an
encouragement to saints who are in those
extended battles, you know. Yeah. Those
extend those storms that seem like they
just will never go away. And um I needed
to hear that personally because it seems
like we've been in the storm since
December or something like that. And
it's almost December again. But guess
what? God is still good and we're still
being blessed. So whoever's watching,
whoever's watching and listening and
you're in your storm and it seems that
you're not coming out the other side.
You can't see the other side. Listen,
you're in the master's hands.
>> You're in his hands. Somebody, your life
is in his hands. And I don't know when
your season's going to be over, but
look, you gonna look back on this right
here and you gonna say with me, if it
hadn't been for the Lord who was on my
side, he was bringing me through. He was
molding me, making me. He was shaping
me. He was deepening me and teaching me
patience and love. Somebody watching,
your season's coming. Hold on.
>> You know, Karen Johnson, I sent you a
message on Facebook Messenger. I don't
know if you saw it, but I was so blessed
by that testimony because we're always
looking for the happy ending obviously,
but it's so important to have that faith
in the hallway before that door is
opened.
>> Yes.
>> Because we don't always see that hope,
that faith, and that strength while
we're waiting on that blessing. Yes. And
I related to this so much because I went
through a period of my of time in my own
life that I called the desert season.
And it was a long wait out of there. I
was a mess.
>> Yeah,
>> I was a mess.
And I never let go of God. Even in my
weakest moments, never let go of God.
And the light at the end of the tunnel
came and his promises came even bigger
and better than I could ever imagine.
>> That's right.
>> Part of that blessing was him that came
in uh
>> the beautiful package he was. But
>> that was just a very small portion of
the blessing. And so hold on.
>> Hold on. Amen. Anyone who is going
through a struggle or a trial and you're
waiting for that that end to come, it
comes in his perfect timing,
>> in his perfect orchestration.
>> It does.
>> So hold on and have faith in that
positivity because God is there and he's
walking alongside you. Even in those
times where you may not feel him, he is
there.
>> Amen. Sound like God talking to somebody
today. Somebody Sound like God trying to
encourage somebody today. Don't give up.
Don't give up, saints.
>> Amen.
>> You are the You're the seed of Abraham,
right? It's 75 years, 100 years between,
you know, I mean, 25 years here. So,
sometimes it just takes us a long time
to get through it, but hold on, saints.
>> Yep.
>> Hold on. Don't give up.
>> Yeah.
>> So, how about some praise reports, my
love?
>> All right. All right. Oh, you know what?
I do have one shout out that we have not
mentioned.
Genesis Meyers had a birthday yesterday.
That is a tante and Ivor's daughter
Genesis. We used to sing with her at
Campbell Church in worship and she is
very special to us. We pray for her
every day
>> and so we just want to say a very happy
and blessed birthday. I know you'll be
celebrating all weekend, but we love you
very much. So, happy birthday, Genesis
Myers.
>> And hello, Jalia.
>> Yes.
>> Hey, Joshua. Okay, he's just gonna shout
out the whole Myers family.
>> Sam, Jaden, Winter, Kyler, goodness,
baby on the way, everybody. Mommy,
Roxan, Papa Ronnie. Hey, look. You start
opening up and here we go.
>> You just take it. You just take it from
here all the way out.
>> Amen.
>> All right,
>> Kevin.
>> Back to praise reports.
Okay, the first one coming from Reed
Witset.
Good day, prayer warriors. I started out
with this prayer request to ask for
prayer for the many things I have been
praying for over the past 10 months. I
was staring at the possibility of losing
many things.
>> I could soon lose access to my digital
communication resources. So, I decided
it was time to share my prayers with the
churches I am part of. It took several
days to get the request legible and in
some kind of order. On Tuesday at 9:16
at 2ish, I was able to complete the now
pages long document and share with our
men's group online before our meeting at
5:30 Pacific Standard Time.
A few minutes after sharing the
document, I got a message from my
daughter. She informed that there was a
financial company attempting to reach
me. I thought I had already closed all
accounts with the company. So I was
curious as to the reason for reaching
out. I had a busy week ahead. So because
of the time constraints of the week, I
decided to respond immediately. The rest
is shared in the document. So I won't
belabor the point here. The events might
seem succinct and immediate, but several
people in our church are aware of my
wife and my struggles. I prayed all
along there would be a praise report in
the story and the Lord may have been
topping tapping on the table awaiting my
request for prayer. So I passed this
story on to you to encourage the
congregate and possibly those in
unbelief that the Lord Almighty is
close. He has likely already provided
the solution to our requests. He
probably identified the perfect
glorified moment to fulfill our requests
and placed our blessing there already.
I'm almost sure he has moved on. Perhaps
he is allowing us to process our request
or insufficiency
or our unbelief or our anxiety, our
fears and or misunderstanding of his
loving grace.
>> Our prayers are likely answered already.
The answers are waiting for us to arrive
at his grace and mercy. So I invite you
to see, just look at what the Lord has
done for me. Believe what he will do for
you. Come to his grace with your request
boldly. Your answers are waiting for you
just like they were waiting for me.
>> Hallelujah.
>> Come out of the wilderness to the new
life Jesus has for you, too. Come to the
radiance of his love and be washed in
greater faith. I'm praying for you just
as you have prayed for me. God bless you
all.
>> Amen.
>> Glory just brought a word right there in
his praise report. We love it.
>> That's how you do it.
from Wendy Allen. Praise time. My
coworker Kathy is healing from her
surgery.
>> Amen.
>> Um from Charlotte Stanforth, she has two
praises. The first one, we've been
praying for Tiffany with Crohn's. An
unfavorable blood report has been ruled
out by the oncologist. Of course, they
were looking for cancer, but he says no.
Hallelujah.
>> Amen.
And her second praise, which Terry
already mentioned, my tech for tonight
in the hospital told me she had just
learned that Sabbath is Saturday, not
Sunday. But she didn't know why that's
important or how it was changed. Well,
she does now because we just did a crash
course. She's so excited and happy.
Praise the Lord. Hallelujah.
>> And her name was Diamond. You said,
"Pray for Diamond."
I caught uh Hattie McDonald's
uh praise report in the chat. She said,
"Visited my physician this week.
Significant weight loss was recorded and
my hypertension diagnosis was removed."
>> All right.
>> Also, hypertension medication was
discontinued.
Thanks be to God.
>> Good stuff. Good stuff.
>> I also saw something in the chat. Let me
see if I can find it. Two seconds. Two
seconds. Two seconds.
>> Amen. While she's looking, we're going
to get ready to go to the throne of
grace. We're seeing your praise re your
prayer requests come in. And our prayer
warriors are definitely um catching
those. Some of you seen them praying for
them already, but we will uh continue to
record them and keep them here. I'm
going to put together a nice prayer
request journal uh with the prayers and
the answers at some point. cuz uh our
prayer warriors do such a wonderful job
of putting a nice uh log together for us
to keep and and it goes way back.
>> Okay. Well, I can't find it, but I
remember someone put a praise report in
the chat that they have a new CL Oh,
here it is. Renee Thomas, God brought me
a new client. Praise God for that. Okay.
Sorry it took me so long to find out.
>> That's all right. I led you to it. And
so and so then saints can remember
continue to send in your uh praise
reports and flood us with them.
Overflood us with them. Maybe we'll take
one power Wednesday and spend that whole
time just sharing praise reports. We
we've done that a couple times. It was a
lot of fun. A lot of fun. And so uh
saints and it's very encouraging. Uh
Shaunene, we will do we will be praying
for your children and your
grandchildren. Sister uh Darthothy uh
yes, we're going to pray about your
black your back and you woke up Thursday
morning with nerves in your back and
they were just firing. you're feeling
better today, but we want to pray that
you'll uh get uh your back is stiff. We
want to pray that you'll get better.
We're taking that to the throne of
grace. Sister Vernette, we're going to
be praying that you will keep your eyes
on Jesus, on the living Christ and
redeemer at all times. We're going to
pray for your three sons that uh the
Lord will shield them from the enemy's
attacks in the name of Jesus. Yes.
Continuing to pray for sister Charlotte.
She has a burden on her heart for El
Moses, which is Living Matter Online
School of Evangelism. Uh we're
definitely going to keep praying about
that. The Lord lays burdens on her heart
for a certain reason and she follows
through with those and then sometimes it
feels like she's coming under attack. So
we want to keep that in prayer and
praying for her witness there where
she's at. Uh we already see how she's
been a blessing to the nurse diamond. Um
uh I want to pray for seven loaves and
fishes of men. The Lord laid that on my
heart today heavily. So I want to
continue to pray for brother Kirk and
brother Elco, brother Kashif, and
brother Ross who have been heading that
up. May God uh blow the wind of his
spirit through there and bless y'all
with a with just a revival of of of a of
refreshing word for those men. U want to
pray for um a young who had co some time
back and so I definitely know what
that's like and praying about that. My
beloved um I am um Garcia has asked to
pray for her brother. Uh
he was an SDA but he got caught up into
some um he is an SDA but he got caught
up into some secret of society. So we
want to pray for your brother uh sister
Garcia. We want to pray for your father
and siblings, your mother for her
health. Uh uh Shellyley Bernavville has
asked um
that uh we would pray for Mary, her
coworker who had a PET scan and wasn't
looking really good. So we're going to
pray about that. Sister Crystal had a
very good interview this week for a new
job there which will allow her to work
from home and as she's working home she
won't have to have a caregiver for
Scarlet. So, which will be working out
well for everybody and so we're
definitely praying for that Crystal that
you will uh do well and get that good
job. Celeb Grace is asking that we pray
uh about her husband who's passing from
stage four cancer uh and for Stephen who
is needs the strength to care for him.
Yeah, we'll definitely be praying for
for that uh Celeb Grace and also for
brother Gavin. His stepfather is going
to be having surgery on Monday or
Tuesday. And we want to definitely keep
Gavin who is our one of our techs uh on
the tech team on the production team.
Keep Brother Gavin in prayer and his
entire family in prayer, particularly
his stepfather. God is able Gavin.
Believe that, brother. He's still a
miracle worker. You can believe that.
You can go before him. Trust him, my
brother. We don't have to just give in
and give up. Want to remember to pray
for Taj and reflections of hope. Uh
beautiful, beautiful message today
reminding us of uh the sweet fragrances
in the world in spite of a world that's
filled with sin and a lot of bad
fragrances. We're that sweet saver and
we have to be that saints. And uh we
also want to uh Andre Ward is asking us
to pray for his girlfriend and her walk
with the Lord. We'll definitely do that.
Sister Charice Henley is asking us to
pray for her co-worker's marriage. Uh,
apparently a hubby had a tough day at
work and a week at work and came home
and may not have been as kind as he
could have been and should have been.
So, we'll definitely be praying for
that. Sister Rose has asked for praying
for healing uh those who have been hurt
by these divisive words that we've been
hearing and some of us who have uh
discovered brothers and sisters who
actually agree or have ignored those
things. praying that God will give us
all healing and reconciliation that that
we would realize sometimes we're playing
checkers while the enemy is playing
chess, not allow him to use these
divisions and divisive things to to
separate us one from another. So, we're
praying about that. Thank you, Rose. And
brother Clint, we're definitely praying
for healing and peace in your life, my
beloved brother. And Kashie has offered
us a prayer request to lay aside
everything and to have this dialogue and
these conversations that we need to
have. And I pray that we'll have those
in a loving spirit
>> that we would recognize who the real
enemy is, saints. Oh my goodness. Thank
the Lord for the word he sent through
pastor and the first ladies for Sabbath
school. We need that. Sister Darth
Clark, remember to pray for your back.
And I think it was
was it
>> Byron?
>> Byron Thomas that Byron is asking us to
pray for his mother Teresa who has
cancer and dementia. and we're praying
for his brother Daryl who's taking care
of his father and for his wife Teresa uh
her for her mental and physical issues.
>> There's a couple more that came. Can I
read on real quick?
>> Sure.
>> Um from Terry Lee, pray for my uncle who
had a heart attack this week. Pray for
his family who is needing strength to
help in his care. from Renee
Hallebertton. Please pray for my
daughter Madison starting school on
Monday after being in and out of the
hospital since May and in therapy five
days a week now down to three days. Also
pray for my other children and family
and Ashley Owens. A very happy 12th
birthday to Julian. We pray that Julian
has an amazing birthday.
>> Yes. And amen. And Ashley, we do see
your praise report there for your your
foot that was healed. So, we do thank
God for that. Sister Ashley Owings, who
is a prayer warrior. Amen. And and and
we're definitely thanking God for you
and Brother John and your family. We're
keeping you guys in prayer. We're
praying on and on. Other prayer requests
that are coming up into the chat. We see
them there. And we're just lifting all
of these up before the Lord. Thank you
for allowing us to spend time with you
today. Let's go to the throne of grace
together. Uh it is it is not just us
praying, but it is us praying together
corporately as a church. Amen. and and
may the Lord be pleased with our
sacrifice of praise today. Precious
Father, as we draw near to the throne of
grace today, you've heard all of these
requests. In fact, Father, we believe by
faith today as your people, people of
the word, people of prophecy, people of
righteousness, people you have known
from before the foundation of the world,
God, people you have called to uh this
hour for such a time as this. We come
before you humbly, Lord. We have nothing
that we could bring, God, that would
give us merit with you. We have nothing,
no righteousness of our own, Lord. No
wisdom, no strength, no giftedness,
nothing we have that we have not
received from you. And so, Lord, we come
to you today humbly, Lord, with broken
spirit and contrite heart. God, we come
boldly to the throne of grace, Lord,
because you have said we could come. We
call on the name above every name
because you have given us that name.
Yeshua Hamashiach, your son, Lord God,
our savior, our sooncoming king, our
healer, our friend that stickketh closer
than a brother, our rock in a weary
land, our shield and fortress. Lord God,
our great high tower, our refuge and
strength. Lord God, you are our only
hope in this world. Lord, show yourself
strong on behalf of those whose hearts
are loyal to you. Thank you for the
blood of the lamb slain from before the
foundation of the world. Thank you,
Lord, that you desire to heal us and
provide for us much more than we ever
could desire that for ourselves because
we are yours. We're the sheep of your
pasture. We're the flock of your foe,
God. You've created us for your purpose
and your pleasure and your desire. God,
have mercy on us, Lord. Forgive us for
our sinfulness. Forgive us for our
selfishness. Forgive us for our pride
and our neglect. Lord, forgive us for
our stubbornness. When you told us to go
left, we went right. Told us to go
right, we went left, told us to move
when we sat still like dumb beasts.
Lord, have mercy on us, oh God, and
change us. Save us, Lord. Pour your
spirit upon us, Lord. Fill us to
overflowing. Transform us, Lord. Renew
our thinking, oh God. Lord, don't allow
the evils of this world and this evil
atmosphere to contaminate us and corrupt
our hearts and our mind. We need you
today, God, and we cannot make it
without you. These things that we've
asked you for, they're nothing for you
to do. For with you all things are
possible. You said, "Seek ye first the
kingdom of God, and his righteousness,
and all these things have been added
will be added unto you." Forgive us for
seeking all these things first and
somehow expecting that the kingdom is
going to be added. Thank you, Lord, for
helping us to get it right in this hour.
Thank you for the word that you continue
to send us, the living word in love. You
send us this word in mercy. You give us
these warnings in mercy and love. Lord
God, you give us this opportunity to be
right with you. And so today together,
Living Mana Church, everyone that's
listening, all of us, we join our
hearts, we join our minds, we join our
faith before you today, oh Lord God, and
we call on you. We call on you to save
us, Lord. You said, "Whosoever shall
call upon the name of the Lord shall be
saved." And so thank you Lord that in
the name of Jesus Christ of Nazareth,
Lord God, the name above every name, you
said every knee shall bow of things in
heaven and in things in in the earth,
division must bow, pride must bow,
sickness and disease must bow, division
must bow, Lord God. Uh uh uh
indifference and coldness must bow,
Lord, and intolerance must bow and
selfishness must bow. pride, Lord,
spiritual pie, deception must bow, oh
Lord, help us to love and serve you,
Lord, with all we have inside of us. And
God, change, we can't, we can't even
give it, Lord. We know it's ours. We
should give it to you. We should
surrender our all to you, but Lord,
we're too weak to even do that. Grant us
the grace, Lord, to surrender to you in
a way that's pleasing to you and to
worship you. Thank you for hearing and
answering these prayers. Help us to be
in the right faith attitude that
sometimes when our miracles come and our
answers come, we're too prideful and
stuck up to see them come. Sometimes we
miss our blessing because we're too busy
begging. We miss our blessing because
we're too busy fighting with one another
and complaining and whispering and
murmuring and gossiping. Fix us, oh
Lord, today in Jesus name. Revive your
work in the midst of the years. This is
our humble prayer today in Jesus name.
And by faith we want to praise you,
Lord. May the joy of the Lord fill our
hearts and fill our minds today, Lord
God. May we worship you in the beauty of
holiness. May we be lights, Lord, and
examples. May folk look up and see us
coming, Lord God, and say as someone
mentioned today that someone said that
that the the Seventh Day Adventist was
the kindest folk they'd ever seen. A
brother who had a a negative attitude
about white Adventist. when he white
people, but when he saw the Seventh Day
Adventist folk, he knew that there's
something different about these people
from every tribe, tongue, and nation.
When folk look at us, may they see
Jesus, God. No matter who we are, where
we're from, what we've done, what we've
come through, may they see nothing but
Jesus, who is a reflection of you, your
goodness, your love, and your glory and
grace. In Jesus name we pray. Amen.
>> Amen.
Amen.
He
[Music]
God of creation
there at the start before the beginning
of time.
M
with no point of reference.
He spoke to the dark and fleshed out the
wonder of light.
And as you speak,
100 billion galaxies are born.
In the vapor of your breath, the planets
fall.
If the stars were made to worship, so
will I.
I can see your hand in everything you've
done.
Every burning star a signal fire of
grace.
If creation sings your praises, so will
I.
So will I.
part of your promise.
You don't speak in vain. No sable left
your voice.
[Music]
For once you have spoken
all nature and science follow the sound
of your voice.
[Music]
And as you speak,
100 billion creatures catch your breath.
Evolving in pursuit of what you say.
If it all reveals your nature, so will
I.
[Music]
So will I.
So we
if the stars were made to worship, so
will I.
If the mountains were made to worship,
so will I.
If the oceans royal praises, so will I.
For if everything exists to lift you
high, so will I.
The wind goes where you send it, so will
I. Oh,
if the rocks cry out in silence, so will
I.
If the song of all our praise is still
for shine,
[Music]
then we'll sing again a h 100 billion
times.
[Music]
Oh
God of salvation,
you chased up my heart through all of my
failure and pride
[Music]
on a hill. You created
the light of the world abandoned in
darkness to die.
And as you speak,
a 100 million failies disappear.
You lost your life so I can find me
here.
If you left the grave behind you. So
alive.
I can see a heart in everything you've
done.
Every part designed and a work of art
love.
If you gladly chose surrender, so will
I.
>> I can see your heart 8 billion different
ways.
Every preious one, the child you die to
save.
If you gave your life to love them, so
will I.
Like you would again a 100 billion
times.
What measure could amount to your
desire?
You're the one who never leave the one
behind.
[Music]
You're the one who never leave the one
behind.
[Music]
Amen. Amen. Happy Sabbath, church
family.
Uh we are getting ready to get into the
word of God today. Um I want to go ahead
and just invite you to click to make
sure you hit the the like button and
make sure you hit the share button. let
people know that the message is getting
ready to be delivered. And once again, I
believe that God has something uh
special in store for uh his people
today. Um I believe that the message
today is is crucial for us. So, we're
going to have a word of prayer. Put a
one in the chat if you're ready to eat
and let's let's get into this word.
Let's get into this word. Heavenly
Father,
Lord, please speak to us as we open the
word. Lord, feed us and fill us. And
Lord, help us
as we uh seek to understand better this
subject
of um of Christianity at a crossroads.
Lord, please open our eyes that we may
see and open our ears that we may hear
is our prayer in Jesus name. Amen. Amen.
Um,
I want to begin this message, an
American crisis,
Christianity
at a crossroads,
with a look of at the
the controversy
that began in heaven.
Um, we'll pick up with our very first
verse, which is found in Revelation
12:7. Let's go to our screen. Uh let's
go to the screen and we're going to go
to Revelation 12 and verse 7. And again,
we're dealing with the subject entitled
An American Crisis: Christianity
at a Crossroads. In Revelation 12 and
verse 7, the Bible tells us um Oh, we
got the wrong slide uh up. So, team, if
you could uh pull that down. I'm just
going to go ahead and read from my notes
here. Um,
Revelation 12 and verse 7. The Bible
says, "And there was war in heaven.
Michael and his angels fought against
the dragon, and the dragon fought and
his angels and prevailed not, neither
was their place found anymore in
heaven." The Bible tells us in the book
of Revelation 12 that there was war in
heaven. That Michael and his angels
fought against the dragon and his angels
and that their place was no longer found
in heaven.
This scene
uh reveals to us that some kind of
conflict, some kind of crisis unfolded
that led to Satan uh who was at one time
Lucifer being cast out of heaven with
his angels.
We can read about this uh this same
event in the book of Isaiah chapter 14
beginning with verse 12. And the Bible
says here, "How art thou fallen from
heaven, oh Lucifer, son of the morning?
How art thou cut down to the ground
which did weaken the nations? For thou
has said in thine heart, I will ascend
into heaven. I will exalt my throne
above the stars of God.
I will sit also upon the mount of the
congregation in the sides of the north.
I will ascend above the heights of the
clouds. I will be like the most high. I
will be like the most high. These are
very serious words uttered by this
angel.
And and I want to suggest to you that
what Lucifer was doing in heaven
was basically claiming that he had the
the power
of God, that he could be his own God,
that he could be just like God.
If we look at yet another verse that
brings that highlights this fall of
Lucifer from heaven, uh we will go to
the book of Ezekiel chapter 28. And we
will notice here Ezekiel 28 is using the
king of Tyrus a as as a symbol or type
of Satan himself. And I want you to
notice what it says here. Son of man,
take up a lamentation upon the king of
Tyrus, and say unto him, Thus sayeth the
Lord God, thou sealest up the sum, full
of wisdom, and perfect in beauty. Thou
has been in Eden, the garden of God.
Every precious stone was thy covering.
The Sardis, the topaz, the diamond, the
barrel, the onyx, and the jasper, the
sapphire, the emerald, and the
carbuncle, and gold. The workmanship of
thy tabs and of thy pipes were prepared
in thee in the day that thou was
created. Thou art the anointed cherub
that coverth. This is speaking of
Lucifer who at one time
served as the anointed cherub in heaven.
And it says, I have said thee so. Thou
has thou was upon the holy mountain of
God. Thou has walked up and down in the
midst of the stones of fire. You were
perfect in your ways from the day that
you were created until
iniquity was found in thee. The Bible
tells us that that Lucifer sinned
and sin according to first John 3:4
is the transgression of God's law.
The Bible tells us that God's law may
basically be summarized in this word
love. God's law is love. And so Lucifer
in essence rejected God's law while also
claiming to be like God. If we put this
together, what Lucifer was in fact
saying in heaven and what he had what he
ended up convincing a third of the
angels in heaven about was this
that you can be your own judge
and determine what is right and what is
wrong for yourself. That is what the law
does. The law tells us what is right and
what is wrong. Lucifer said, "I can be
like God. I can be holy like God without
a law dictating to me what is right and
what is wrong. I can and I want you to
put this word in the chat for me. I can
judge
for myself.
I can judge
Now
I want you to note with me. Let's go
back to our slides and we're going to
pick up in verse 16.
Still speaking of Lucifer, the text
says, "By the multitude of thy
merchandise, they have filled the midst
of thee with violence, and thou hast
sinned. Therefore, I will cast thee as
profane out of the mountain of God, and
I will destroy thee, oh covering cherub,
from the midst of the stones of fire.
Thine heart was lifted up because of thy
beauty. Thou has corrupted thy wisdom by
reason of thy brightness. I will cast
thee to the ground. I will lay thee
before kings that they may behold thee.
So, let's break this down for a moment.
Lucifer
is about to be cast out of heaven.
And the Bible says that God says to
Lucifer, I'm going to lay you before
kings
that are going to behold you. In other
words, what are you saying is, I'm going
to bring you before kings that are going
to judge you. And you will see that the
Bible actually confirms this in a
moment. And so, nonetheless, Lucifer is
cast out and he's told that God is going
to raise up some kings that are going to
judge him. Now, I want you to note the
significance of what you've just heard
in the book of Deuteronomy
when God is speaking to Moses and God is
laying out rules for how the children of
Israel are going to going to function,
especially in terms of justice. Here's
what the Bible says.
Deuteronomy 19:16-1 17. If a false
witness rise up against any man to
testify against him that which is wrong,
then both the men between whom the
controversy is, shall stand before the
Lord, before the priests and the judges,
which shall be in those days.
And the judges shall make diligent
inquisition. And behold, if the witness
be a false witness, and has testified
falsely against his brother, then ye
shall do unto him as he thought to have
done unto his brother, so shalt thou put
away the evil from among you. So note
the principle here. God said whenever
controversy arises between two people or
two parties, there must be a third party
that will judge between the two.
Almost like a jury
and that's a very fair principle. the
person being accused.
Neither the person being accused nor the
accuser should serve as the judge in the
case because it would it would be
considered to be impartial or or rather
partial.
It would be considered to be unfair.
Now, taking this principle and we're
coming some we're going somewhere very
important with this you guys. taking
this principle back into this war that
happened in heaven. I need you to
understand something
in heaven. And this is before the
creation of the world. This fall of
Lucifer happens before man has been
created.
When this conflict unfolds,
there is God and his angels and there is
a devil and his angels.
All heaven is split into two into two
sides.
So when God says to Lucifer, "Lucifer,
I'm going to lay you before kings
that are going to behold you, in
essence, that are going to judge you."
Who is he talking about?
Who were these kings that God was going
to give judgment to to judge the devil
and his angels? Let me read it to you
from the book of 1 Corinthians chapter 6
verse 2. The Bible says, "Do you not
know that the saints shall judge the
world? And if the world shall be judged
by you, are you unworthy to judge the
smallest matters?" Verse three, "Know
you not." Oh wow, where is verse three?
It is not in my slide. So I'm just going
to read it. Know you not. The Bible says
that we shall judge angels. Somebody put
that text in the chat for me if you can.
I actually think I saw someone quote it
already. 1 Corinthians chapter 6:3 tells
us that the saints
will judge angels, not holy angels, not
right righteous angels,
fallen angels, wicked angels.
And this judgment does not occur
until Jesus comes and gets his saints at
the very end of time.
So what I want you to understand now is
that when God created mankind,
it was in part
to serve as jurors
to judge the devil and his angels.
And this is very important to understand
beloved because
when a jury is selected certain things
must be in place. Number one jurors
cannot have knowledge of the crime when
it happened. In other words, they could
not jurors
cannot have been present at the crime.
Where was mankind when God and his
angels and the devil and his angels were
waring in heaven? Mankind was not there.
So number one, the newly created Adam
and Eve absolutely fit that description.
They were not there at the time of the
crime. Number two, jurors must be
law-abiding citizens.
Were Adam and Eve law-abiding citizens?
Did Adam and Eve have the law of God
written upon their hearts? The law of
love? The answer is yes. They absolutely
did. Number three, a juror must know the
difference between right and wrong. Did
Adam and Eve know the difference between
right and wrong? Absolutely. Because God
told them, you'll remember, God said,
"Eat from this tree and it will lead to
death.
Eat from the tree of life and it will
lead to life. So then so then
we know that that Adam and Eve had the
knowledge of good and evil. They knew
good and evil. Satan tempted them with
something they already had. Uh uh they
were not there at the time of the crime
and they were law-abiding citizens.
Number four, listen to this. Number
four, a juror must not be swayed by
public opinion.
Amen. A juror must not be swayed by
public opinion. Now, listen very
carefully.
If you were a criminal and you knew that
the jury had your fate in their hands
and you were corrupt,
what else would you do but try to bribe
the jury?
Come on, let's go to Genesis chapter 6.
Genesis chapter 6,
Genesis chapter
three, rather, I'm sorry, Genesis
chapter 3 and um
verse one, the Bible says, "Now the
serpent was more subtle than any beast
of the field which the Lord God had
made.
And he said unto the woman, Yay, has God
said, 'You shall not eat of every tree
of the garden?" And the woman said unto
the serpent, "We may eat of the fruit of
the trees of the garden, but of the
fruit of the tree which is in which is
in the midst of the garden." God has
said, "You shall not eat of it, neither
shall you touch it, lest you die,
lest you die." And the serpent said unto
the woman, "You shall not surely die.
For God does know that in the days you
eat thereof, then your eyes shall be
open, and ye shall be as God's. Now, the
word there for God's may be understood
as judges.
You will be your own judges, knowing
good and evil. In other words, the very
same thing
that Lucifer
trafficked to angels in heaven,
the very thing that he trafficked in
heaven, you can be your own God. You can
be your own judge. You can know the
difference between right and wrong for
yourself without listening to God is the
very thing that he attempts to bribe the
jury with.
And
what happens? The Bible tells us that
the woman saw that the tree was good for
food and it was pleasant to the eyes and
a tree to be desired to make one wise.
She took of the fruit and did eat and
gave also unto her husband with her and
he did eat and the eyes of them both
were opened and they knew that they were
naked and they sowed fig leaves
together. I need you to understand that
if we go back to Genesis uh to uh to
Revelation
1:5, the Bible says this, speaking of
Jesus Christ, who is a faithful witness
and the first begotten of the dead, and
the prince of the kings of the earth
unto him that loved us and washed us
from our sins in his own blood, and has
made us kings and priests unto God and
to his father. Come back for a moment.
When the Bible tells us that God was
going to lay Lucifer before kings that
were to behold him and judge him, he was
talking about humanity.
And so the devil understood, hey, if I
can bribe the jury, then there will be
no case. Humanity was to be that third
party. Deuteronomy chapter 19,
that third party that was to judge
Lucifer. But Lucifer said, "Hey, if I
can bribe the jury and get them to
follow my path,
then
there will be no judgment."
There will be no judgment.
Why am I bringing this up right now?
Why did I do that that that whole
leadup?
Right now,
there are many people that are judging
um
Charlie Kurt,
judging whether he was righteous
or wicked, judging whether he was a
saint or a sinner. And and I only use
this as an example right now to show how
as human beings we are very prone to
judging according
to our own judgment.
We are very prone to judging according
to the information
that we have.
And so we judge based off of videos or
we judge based off of smaller videos. We
judge based off of clips. We judge based
off of what we've heard. We judge not
understanding
what 1st Samuel
16 and verse 7 says, which is, "For man
lookketh on the outward appearance, but
the Lord lookketh on the heart." Y'all
put a one in the chat if you get if that
if that makes sense to you. If you
understand what the Bible is saying,
man judges based on outward appearance.
Man judges based on the information that
he is able to to gather.
But there's a problem with that
because more often than not, our
judgment
is imprecise.
Our judgment
is faulty.
Which is why we are actually told,
"Judge not
that you be not judged."
You see, beloved,
the entire plan of salvation
involves
God restoring humanity,
restoring mankind to being sound jurors
who know the difference between right
and wrong.
Are y'all with me?
God calls us, says I I'm my goal in the
gospel is to bring you back into
accordance with my will.
But what often happens is that thing
that happened to Adam and Eve in the
garden, hey, you can judge for yourself.
You can know for yourself the difference
between right and wrong
without following God's law, without
following God's word.
We often take that upon ourselves even
in the Christian world. The Bible says
in Isaiah chapter 5, "Woe unto those
that call good evil and call evil good."
And I can hear every possible Christian
on the planet now saying that's right.
Thinking that they are the ones that
understand rightly what that what evil
actually is and what good actually is
and yet are disagreeing with each other
on what good is and what evil is.
Let me give you an example.
Let's say we were living back in the
days of Jesus and we're all we're all uh
um you know believers in God
and we're watching this crucifixion of
Jesus Christ and at some point we had to
leave early. We had to leave early but
but here's the last thing we saw at the
crucifixion.
Matthew 27:43.
So the people are mocking Jesus. They
said he trusted in God. Let him deliver
him now if he will save him. For he
said, I am the son of God. The thieves
also which were crucified with him cast
the same in his teeth. Okay. So
something happens and you had to leave
early. You go home. The last thing you
saw
were two thieves on the cross
mocking Jesus.
Come on y'all.
What do you think?
Let's just say you were you were a
follower of Christ and
or you weren't a follower of Christ,
but the last thing you saw
was that thief mocking one of those
thieves, both thieves mocking Jesus.
You go home, what do you think? You
become a Christian maybe years later.
So, you don't know the story of what
happened at the cross. What do you think
about that thief on the cross? That guy
is what?
Put it in the chat for me, please. What
do you think? That man is
lost.
And you might even rehearse all the
wicked things he had done in his life.
You know why he's up there on the cross?
Yeah, this man's a crook. He's no good.
He's this. He's that. and you're going
down the list of all the things you
remember about the man.
You weren't there to hear him in his
last dying breath.
His last dying breath. You weren't there
to hear him say,
"Remember me when you come into your
kingdom."
But God heard it.
God heard it.
And here you walk away thinking, "Yeah,
man. That that thief on the cross, he
was on drugs. He doesn't deserve
sympathy. He doesn't deserve he's a lost
man."
Meanwhile, you you remember the Pharisee
leaders, right? So, here are the
Pharisees
and they are these are, you know, they
don't eat unclean foods. The Pharisees,
the leaders, these are the top guys,
they don't eat unclean foods. They're
zealous for the truth. Um, they they
keep the commandments.
Where do you think they're going?
Yeah, they they must be in heaven.
Or watch this. You might be you might
know that all the Pharisees are wicked.
You know that.
And you know there's a guy named
Nicodemus.
Now you don't know you know you you're
not following Nicodemus. You don't have
time for that. You got your life to
live. But you know that Nicodemus is one
of the Pharisees. And so in your mind
you're thinking, man, all those
Pharisees are wicked. Remember what
Jesus said about the Pharisees? They're
all wicked.
Come on, y'all. Do you understand?
Do you understand why human judgment is
so faulty?
Do you understand why
it is unsafe
for us as humans
to judge?
That's right. Somebody said, "You mean
Nicodem?"
Yeah. Not Nicodemus. Nicodemus. That
that that wicked that wicked Pharisee
because you just assumed that all
Pharisees were wicked in every category.
Wow.
I would have never thought
that they would be lost or that person
would be saved.
And beloved, I'm about to say something
to you now.
This is why
this is why
this is why there is a judgment
that is operated by God himself.
It's really amazing to me how how
Christians say a lot of Christians say,
"Oh, this idea of God having a judgment,
uh, you know, that's not biblical." And
why would God need a judgment?
Let me tell you why, beloved. Because it
it will take God himself to convince
some of us that some people should not
have a right to heaven
and that some people should be in heaven
because left up to us, we will argue
with God as to why somebody should be
saved and why somebody should be lost.
Are are y'all following what I'm saying
here?
This is why our church in particular
teaches this thing called the
investigative judgment
where God himself
makes right
all the erroneous human judgments.
Think about how many people judge people
and say, "Oh, yeah, man. That person,
you know, saint, that person sinner."
Think about how and think about how
society is affected by this and how
sometimes
that faulty judgment damages the witness
of Christianity.
We put wicked people in hell and
righteous people we we put wicked people
in heaven and righteous people in hell
and we call this judgment righteous.
This is why God has not left it up to us
to judge
or to demand a verdict on a person's
life.
They were this. You don't know. Do you
know what this person or that person or
that person were doing behind closed
doors? You don't know, do you?
No. No. No. Come with me to Revelation
14 6 and 7 where the Bible says, "And I
saw another angel fly in the midst of
heaven, having the everlasting gospel to
preach unto them that dwell on the earth
and to every nation and kindred and
tongue and people, saying with a loud
voice, fear God and give glory to him,
for the hour of his judgment is come,
and worship him that made heaven and the
earth and the sea and the fountains of
waters." The hour of his judgment is
come.
Now beloved, listen. If we can scarcely
judge our own families,
you know, um I've lived with this
person. I know this person. And um I
know this person was a good person.
And still you may not know that person
as well as you thought you knew that
person. But if we can barely judge
people that we know,
how can we get to the place
where we can confidently
judge people
that we've never met?
Now, please don't get me wrong. The
Bible says by their fruit you shall know
them. And we can look at fruit and say,
"Yeah, by the fruit this is what I see.
But I know that I'm not God and so I
haven't seen all the fruit. And because
I haven't seen all the fruit, I cannot
make a judgment.
But from the fruit that I have seen, God
says, you can look at that and say,
"Yes, this or that." But beloved, it's
not our place to put people in heaven or
to put people in hell.
You don't even know the silent
conversations that are going on as that
person is laying in a coma.
If God is communicating with them, you
don't know
that last dying thought of that man
who was a KKK
loving
racist as whatever.
You don't know that person's last
thought in his mind as he's dying. He's
saying, "Lord, how could I have been so
deceived? Forgive me. Remember me when
you come into your kingdom." You also
don't know the last dying thought of the
man who was out there preaching and
teaching and and witnessing and doing
all these things.
But the double life he had been living,
she had been living. You don't know.
And beloved, this is why if you're not
if you're not a Seventh Day Adventist
and you may be listening to this sermon
for the first time, this is why we
believe in this biblical thing called
the investigative judgment.
Because the investigative judgment is
God writing the records of those who
have been wrong. Is God reversing
judgments that people have erroneously
made?
Which incidentally is why we
definitely ought not
to be in the business
of putting people in heaven or hell.
There's a judgment. In fact, in Daniel
chapter 7, in Daniel 7:9, the Bible
says, "I beheld to thrones were cast
down, and the ancient of days did sit,
whose garment was white as snow, and the
hair of his head like the pure wool. His
throne was like the fiery flame, and his
wheels as burning fire. A fiery stream
issued and came forth from before him.
Thousands times thousands ministered
unto him, and 10,000 times 10,000 stood
before him. The judgment was set and the
books were open. You see beloved, God
has the complete record and him only. On
only God has the books.
Listen to me y'all. Every one of us has
a file. Epstein has a file. You have a
file. You have a file. All of us have a
file. Here,
here, let me let me show you. Let me
show you. Eccle, Ecclesiastes chapter
12, verse 13 and 14. Let us hear the
conclusion of the whole matter. Fear God
and keep his commandments, for this is
the whole duty of man. For God shall
bring every work into judgment with
every secret thing, whether it be good
or whether it be evil.
Are y'all following me?
If I can say it this way, I believe that
the devil
is trying to get us to judge
unrighteously,
to call evil good and to call good evil.
This is why, beloved, it is very
important for us to understand that
while God has called us to be jurors,
we're not those jurors yet.
We're not those jurors yet. So, we need
to understand, Lord, you know what? My
judgment is faulty. So, while I've seen
these fruits, I'm still not going to
condemn this person to hell. Or while
I've seen these fruits, I'm still not
going to be like, "Yep, he was a saint."
No, let me step back because God only
you know and when I decide to get into a
war with with with other people to
demand that they see
that they go along with my judgment.
We're in trouble as a church. We're in
trouble as Christians
because this is going somewhere.
You're going to see something unfolding.
But just watch this here. Watch this
guys. So that word for judgment.
That word for judgment means measure.
Judgment is God measuring.
That's what it is.
God is measuring you according to a
standard. So the question is what is he
measuring? And and here's where I want
y'all to begin to see something,
beloved. Because this comes down to the
heart of what is Christianity cuz many
of us don't even many of us don't know
what Christianity actually is. We think
it's one thing when it's something else.
So watch this. In Revelation 11:1, the
Bible says, "There was given me a reed
like unto a rod, and the angel stood,
saying, rise and measure the temple of
God and the altar, and them that worship
therein."
Here is a symbolic call to measure this
temple and those that worship in the
temple. Why is this significant? There's
a measurement going on here.
What is this temple? In Exodus 25:8,
the Bible says these words, God is
speaking to the children of Israel, and
he's about to introduce to them this
thing called a sanctuary. And he says
here, "Let them make me a sanctuary,
that I may dwell among them, according
to the pattern that I shall show thee,
show thee, and the pattern of the
tabernacle, and the pattern of all the
instruments thereof, even so shall ye
make it." Now, watch this. The very next
verse begins with the measurement of
this thing called the ark of the
covenant.
They shall make an arc of wood. Two
cubits and a half shall be the length
thereof, and a cubit and a half the
breadth thereof, and a cubit and a half
the height thereof.
Verse 7 16- 17. And thou shalt put into
the ark the testimony that I shall give
thee. And thou shalt make a mercy seat
of pure gold. Two cubits and a half
shall be the length thereof, and a cubit
and a half the breadth thereof. The
first thing that is measured in this
sanctuary is the ark of the covenant and
the mercy seat. What is in the ark of
the covenant? It is the law of God which
we described earlier as the law of love.
On top of that law is the mercy seat. In
other words, beloved, the way God
measures is by our love and mercy.
Put a five in the chat.
Put a five in the chat if you see what
I'm saying. God measures. He says,
"Measure the temple and then that
worship therein."
When we go back to the temple, we see
the very first thing that God says to
measure in the temple
is the ark of the covenant and the mercy
seat. The ark of the covenant had the
law of God in it and the mercy seat
rested on top of the ark. God judges
love and mercy.
Zechariah chapter 6. Note with me
Zechariah 6 verse 12. It says, "Speak
unto him, saying, thus sayith, thus
speaketh the Lord of hosts, saying,
behold the man whose name is a branch.
He shall grow up out of his place and he
shall build the temple of the Lord. He
shall even build the temple of the Lord
and shall bear the glory and shall sit
and rule upon his throne. Now I want you
to understand something here. This is
the Old Testament which would also
parallel the Old Covenant. In the Old
Covenant, the sanctuary was among the
people. Let them make me a sanctuary
that I may dwell among them. Think of
that as the old covenant.
But now Jesus, the one who was
prophesied to build the temple of the
Lord. What do you mean build the temple
of the Lord, pastor? Why is the text
saying that Jesus would build the temple
of the Lord if there's a temple already
in the Old Testament? Listen.
In the book of Matthew 1:23, the Bible
tells us this. Behold, a virgin shall be
with child and shall bring forth a son.
And they shall call his name Emmanuel,
which being interpreted is God with us.
You see, beloved, Jesus himself became
the embodiment of the sanctuary. In the
Old Testament, let them make me a
sanctuary that I may dwell among them.
In the New Testament, thou shalt call
his name Emanuel, meaning God with us.
Just as the very presence of God was in
that sanctuary in the Old Testament, so
the very presence of God is in Jesus,
the man Jesus in the New Testament. And
so the Bible tells us in John 1:14, "The
word was made flesh and dwelt among us.
And we beheld his glory, the glory as of
the only begotten of the Father, full of
grace and truth. He himself was God
manifest in the flesh. Put these words
in the chat for me, please. Manifest in
the flesh. Jesus was God in
the flesh.
Hold that thought and I want you to
watch this. In John chapter 2:18, the
Jews answered and said unto him, Jesus,
"What sign showest thou unto us, seeing
that thou do these things?" Jesus
answered and said unto them, "Destroy
this temple, and in three days I will
raise it up." Then said the Jews, 40 and
six years have we been building this
temple that have we have 40 and six
years was this temple in building, and
will thou rare it up in three days? But
he spake of the temple of his body. Are
y'all following this? In the New
Testament, Jesus himself is the temple.
You're saying, "Pastor, where are you
going with this? Follow me. Watch this.
Listen carefully."
You see, in the book of Acts, Acts
chapter 2, the disciples are gathered
together praying. And the Bible says on
the day of pent, when the day of
Pentecost was fully come, they were all
with one accord in one place. And
suddenly, or in one place, and suddenly
there came a sound from heaven, as of a
rushing mighty wind, and it filled all
the house where they were sitting, and
there appeared unto them clothed tongues
like as a fire, and it sat upon each of
them, and they were all filled
with the Holy Ghost.
Put that word in the chat for me,
please.
They were all filled with the Holy
Ghost. Here's what I want you to get,
beloved. In the Old Testament,
God dwelt among his people.
On the day of Acts,
God is now dwelling in his people.
The Holy Spirit
filled them.
First, Exodus 40:34.
When the temple of God was completed in
the Old Testament, the Bible says, "Then
a cloud covered the tent of the
congregation, and the glory of the Lord
filled the tabernacle." The Bible tells
us in 1 Corinthians 3:16, "Know ye not
that you are the temple of God, and that
the spirit of God dwelleth in you? If
any man defile his temple, him shall God
destroy. For the temple of God is holy,
which temple you are." In other words,
beloved,
the difference between the old covenant
and the new covenant is in the old
covenant, God was dwelling among his
people, but in the new covenant, God is
dwelling in his people. Meaning beloved
that the definition of a Christian is
one who has Jesus in him.
One who has Jesus in her.
Let me say it this way.
It is one thing to have information
about Jesus
and like that information and be
thrilled about that information and say
yes Jesus is the only way and to say yes
Jesus is the truth and to say yes this
doctrine is right and this doctrine is
wrong and to say yes this position is
right and this position is wrong. It is
one thing to exper It is one thing to
have information.
It is another thing to experience
incarnation.
Incarnation is God manifest in the
flesh.
You see, there's a reason why in the
book of Hebrews, in the book of Hebrews
chapter 10, the Bible says, "Wherefore
the Holy Ghost is also a witness to us.
For after that he said before this is
the covenant that I will make with them
after those days sayith the Lord I will
put my laws into their hearts and in
their minds will I write them. That's
pretty deep you guys. That's pretty
deep. In fact
in fact Ezekiel 36:26
which is the new covenant stated in the
old covenant in the Old Testament is
this. A new heart also will I give you,
and a new spirit will I put within you,
and I will take away the stony heart out
of your flesh, and I will give you a
heart of flesh. Listen,
it is one
information does not make you a
Christian.
Incarnation
is what makes you a Christian.
A Christian
is one who has Christ in
you can have positions. You guys
see listen in our mind in today's
society American Christianity today says
you are a Christian if you have the
right positions on in if you have the
right information. What's your position
on this? What's your position on that?
What's your position on that? Oh, you
checklist all the right positions. You
are a Christian. Woohoo.
The Bible says in Colossians 1 25,
wherefore I am made a minister according
to the dispensation of God, which is
given to me for you to fulfill the word
of God. to fulfill the word of God, even
the mystery which has been hidden from
ages and from generations, but now is
made manifest to his saints, to whom God
would make known what is the riches of
the glory of this mystery among the
Gentiles, which is Christ in you the
hope of glory. Listen to me. American
Christianity is at a crossroads
because the idea that is very popular
now within Christian churches is that if
you hold the right positions,
you are a Christian.
If you if you hold the right position on
abortion, if you hold the right position
on marriage, if you hold the right
position even on the Sabbath,
Seventh Day Adventists,
if you hold the right position on the
law, if you hold the right position on
grace, if you hold the right position,
what's your position? Are you left or
are you right? Are you progressive or
are you conservative? What's your
position on this culture issue? And
what's your position on that c? Oh, you
check off you, my friend, are a
Christian.
And so what ends up happening is we
produce this righteousness by place
instead of righteousness by faith.
Righteousness by position.
What's your position?
All right, listen that. because you hold
the same position I do. We're down.
We're family. Listen, man. That That's
it. We're good. We're good. The true
battle, beloved, is not over position,
but it is over the presence of Christ in
you. You can hold all the right
positions and look like a lamb and yet
speak like a dragon.
In fact, in Revelation 13:1,
there is a symbol. We're not going to
get into what this symbol means right
now, but I just simply want you to
understand that this is this symbol
represents a thing, an entity, a power
that
has the horns of a lamb. That means it
looks
like Jesus.
The lamb representing Jesus in the
Bible. It looks Christian. It looks
Christlike. But when it opens its mouth,
you can know
this is the dragon.
Beloved, it's one thing to judge by the
appearance
because man judges after the appearance.
And beloved, what I want you to
understand is that
Christianity
it's it's in a place right now where
hey,
your position determines your
righteousness.
What else is this but righteousness by
place?
righteousness by position.
Christ, he's out here, but he's not in
the heart. You see, out of the abundance
of the heart, the mouth speaketh. If
Christ is in you, if Christ is in you,
you're going to reflect the character of
Christ.
I want you to note this. 2 Timothy 3:1-3
says this. This know also that in the
last days perilous time shall come. For
men shall be lovers of their of their
own selves, covetous, boasters, proud,
blasphemers, disobedient to parents,
unthankful, unholy, without natural
affection, truth breakers, false
accusers, incontinent, fierce, despisers
of those that are good,
traitors, heady, high-minded, lovers of
pleasure more than lovers of God, having
a form of ungodliness.
Oh, I'm sorry. Having a form of ungodly
Oh, my bad. My bad.
having a form of godliness
but denying the power thereof from such
turn away. In other words, the Bible's
trying to tell us, listen, just because
something looks Christian doesn't mean
that it is Christian. It can have the
form but lack the power. This is why the
text says in Matthew 7 19, every tree
that bringeth forth not good fruit is
heuned down and cast into the fire.
Wherefore by their fruit you shall know
them. Not everyone that saith unto me,
Lord, Lord, shall enter the kingdom of
heaven, but he that doeth the will of my
father which is in heaven. In other
words, it's not just about saying, it's
about doing.
It's not just about the outward
appearance.
It's about actually living out
Christianity. And it's not living out
Christianity does not mean living out
the information or the positions that
you stand on.
Living out Christianity means living out
the life of Christ.
What would Jesus do?
How would Jesus do it?
How would Jesus say it? What would Jesus
say?
You see
John 16:2,
it's a very sobering words.
They shall put you out of the synagogue.
Yay, the time is coming that whosoever
whosoever kills you will think that he
is doing God's service and these things
they will do unto you because they have
not known the father or me. that Jesus
is literally saying that a time is
coming
in the future where there will be people
who profess to be followers of God but
have animosity, hatred, anger in their
hearts enough to drive them to kill.
That's an insane thought, you guys.
Come on, note with me. We're almost
there, guys. We are almost there.
Revelation 14:12, the Bible says, "Here
is the patience of the saints. Here are
they that keep the commandments of God
and the faith of Jesus." You see, it's
not just about an outward obedience to
the law of God. It's not just about
outward conformity. You have to have the
faith of Jesus. Something has to be
going on inside.
It it we see it again in Revelation
12:17. The dragon was wroth with the
woman and went to make war with the
remnant of her seed, which keep the
commandments of God. and have the
testimony of Jesus Christ. You can
actually obey. You can actually keep the
commandments of God and not have the
testimony of Jesus Christ.
Because while you keep the commandments,
while you observe the law, while you
keep the Sabbath,
your words
are vile.
your interaction,
your love for other people
is vile.
And beloved, the problem is if that can
be palmed off for genuine Christianity,
then there is a massive problem
that the church will face.
Because you see,
when we bring Christ down
to a level based on our judgment, this
is what Christianity is. It's the right
positions.
And if you hold the right positions,
doesn't matter how you treat people. If
you hold the right positions, doesn't
matter what comes out your mouth. If you
hold the right positions, doesn't matter
if you hate this person or that person
or if you're prejudiced against this
person or that person. Doesn't matter.
It is crazy to me that there there is a
group of of individuals
who believe and we talked about this in
Sabbath school
who believe that all white people are
lost. They believe in Jesus. They
believe the Bible
and they teach that white people
are lost
and that this is Jesus. This is Jesus's
desire.
How can we hold on to a Jesus that
allows us to hate anybody
of another race, of another country,
of another party?
What Jesus is that?
That is not the Jesus of the Bible.
And yet here we are
at a crossroads.
The Bible says in Matthew chap 24:12 and
13, "Because iniquity shall abound, the
love of many shall wax cold, but he that
endureth unto the end, the same shall be
saved." I need you to understand when
God says, "Measure the temple and them
that worship worship therein." He's
measuring how much love you have. That's
how God judges.
How much love and mercy.
See, listen to me, y'all. Listen to me.
Your mentality must be so
when when when
the resurrection happens and and Stephen
sees
Paul
who was
at one time Saul.
How do you think Stephen is going to
react when he sees Paul?
Paul is the one that resided over him
being stoned. How do you think Stephen
is going to respond?
Do you understand that some people will
not be in heaven because they would
rather not be in heaven with other
people because they have that much hate
in their hearts?
When Stephen sees Paul in heaven, when
that resurrection day comes, Stephen is
not going to be like, "What are you
doing here? Hold on, God. We need to
have a conversation cuz what? That's the
guy that killed me. He's not going to do
that."
But within the Christian church, our
hearts are so filled with hatred for the
other.
For the other,
anger,
wrath, you're not like Jesus, and
therefore we hate your side.
The Bible is telling us that God is
going to measure our love. Notice with
me Ephesians chapter 3:1 17. That Christ
may dwell in your hearts, in your hearts
by faith, that you being rooted and
grounded in love, may be able to
comprehend with all saints what is the
breadth and length and depth and height,
and to know the love of Christ, which
passes knowledge, passes knowledge, that
you may be filled with all the fullness
of God.
Or we can look at Ephesians chapter 4.
Let no corrupt communication proceed out
of your mouth, but that which is good to
the use of edifying, that it may
minister grace unto the hearers. And
grieve not the Holy Spirit of God,
whereby you are sealed unto the day of
redemption. Let all bitterness and wrath
and anger and clamor and evil speaking
be put away from you with all malice.
And be ye kind one to another,
tender-hearted, forgiving one another,
even as God for Christ's sake has
forgiven you.
Do you know what I'm seeing in
Christianity today is so scary.
What I'm seeing in Christianity today is
terrifying.
It is terrifying
that we in the name of God can excuse a
wrathful and angry and vengeful spirit
in the name of Jesus.
It is a scary thing
in Christianity today. It is all about
position
and not about Christ in you. You got the
right positions. You can be as as mean
and as and as sharp and and as witty as
you want. As long as you got the right
position, we're good with it. And this
is blasphemy
in the eyes of God.
He tells us in Romans that the Gentiles
blaspheme the name of God through your
example.
You see,
when Jesus comes again, everyone that is
redeemed, judgment is going to be given
un they will become the the the there is
a judgment that happens during the
10,000 years and only the redeemed take
part of that judgment. In other words,
only jurors will be saved. And remember
beloved, jurors must be law-abiding
citizens of the kingdom of heaven, must
be able to discern between right and
wrong, and must not be swayed by public
opinion. So the devil knows if he can
get you to judge wrong, he's eliminating
you from the jury pool. If he can get
you to call good evil and evil good,
and if he can get you to do it in the
name of Jesus,
how can God
allow a juror into the jury pool that is
going to judge corruptly?
And so the devil is simply trying to
mess up your judgment, based on your
desires, based on your likes, based on
your prejudices. And he's turning around
saying to God, "Can't use her. Look at
what she can't use him. Look, can't use
them. And if you have no judges, how are
you going to judge me?"
So, I want to close with this story.
Uh,
it's a fictional story, but I think
it'll serve the point well.
When I was uh
I mean, this is not fictional,
but what I'm about to tell you is a
fictional uh h account. It's a movie.
When I was younger, um, there was a
movie that came out called The Invasion
of the Body Snatchers.
I believe the movie came out in the 50s
and then it was um, it was they remade
it in the 70s and then again I think in
the 80s or the 90s. So, it was called
The Invasion of the Body Snatchers. And
what this movie was about was was these
these alien pods had come from outer
space and they hit Earth and they needed
a a host to live in. And so what would
happen is when people went to sleep, I
don't know if y'all are hearing me.
When people went to sleep, these pods
would would would would basically take
the person over, create a new person
altogether. And when the person came to
when the person woke up, they were no
longer themselves. They had no emotion.
They were emotionless
beings.
And and at first, no one knew what was
going on. But the more the more time
went on and you found more and more
people being
emotionless and the people who were
seeing this were like wait a minute
something's going on you know and they
began to discover that it was while
while men slept
that this spirit that this coldness this
inhuman thing had taken them over. And
so the whole theme of the movie now was
don't fall asleep.
Don't fall asleep. Because if you fall
asleep, what's going to happen is you
too will become emotionless. You too
will become cold. You too will have no
love.
And but I'm looking around right now and
and I'm kind of getting
this sense of
Christian body snatchers,
pod people.
this normalization
of wrath and anger
towards those that disagree
with the Christian
and I remember in the movie anytime they
when they got into the majority anytime
they saw someone that expressed emotion
it was scar they would be like they'd
point and just it was it it was
traumatizing to me actually
but they would point someone with
emotion And then they would all start
chasing the person.
What a dreadful thought
that that it seems like Christianity is
now getting to the place where
we're now exposing people
who don't think like we think and who
don't respond like we respond. And now
and I
it's it's it's
now acceptable
to be angry
to be wrathful
and beloved it is my fear
that this this Christianity
which is replacing genuine Christianity
that when this Christianity becomes the
norm, it is simply the setup for what we
have been preaching will happen in
Revelation chapter 13
where a a a Christian
nationalist movement in the name of
Jesus
will seek to compel all
to have the same emotions
towards God. Compel all to honor what
they want honored and reject what they
want rejected.
This is not Christianity.
That's not the Christianity of the
Bible.
But it is it is definitely
becoming the most vocal form
of Christianity.
The question now becomes
which Christianity are you going to
adopt? Because we're at a crossroads.
Things will never go back.
We're at a new place.
How are we going to move forward? Are we
going to defend the name of Jesus
by living out his principles of
righteousness and truth and holiness?
Yes, positions matter, but that is not
all that matters.
You can have the right position and not
have Jesus and you are not you. You
don't have Jesus, you have nothing.
That's right. Christians can get angry
at hate, hypocrisy, sin, and vileeness.
And you know how they take out their
anger?
By loving
just like Jesus did.
Jesus loved
That's the Christianity of the Bible.
So the question is which road are you
going to take? Which Christianity will
you live by?
Righteousness by place
or righteousness by faith?
Put a one in the chat. Put a one in the
chat if you're saying to yourself,
"Lord, help me. Help me
to not be enraged
and experience a wrathful type of
Christianity,
a vengeful Christianity,
an angry Christianity.
If the love of many will wax cold, there
will come a time where people will be
like, "There's one with love. get them.
Because if you're not down with the
wrath, if you're not down with the
anger, if you're not down with the with
the outrage,
you will be pointed out.
Jesus told us that time is coming.
And the only way to be ready for it is
to protect the love that is in your
heart. Don't go to sleep, y'all.
Please
don't go to sleep.
Stay
awake.
Stay awake.
Pray with me. Heavenly Father,
Lord, help us not to sleep.
Help us not to close our eyes.
to love, to peace, to truth, to
righteousness,
to what it means to be a Christ
follower.
Lord, we know that if we close our eyes,
if we sleep,
we will be infected with the wrath
of the enemy.
And that's what he's doing right now,
Lord. He's seeking He's seeking to to to
wither away love, to make love wax cold.
So Lord, please, I pray, protect us.
Protect our hearts that they may not
grow cold, that they may not become
stonlike.
And Lord, forgive us
for misrepresenting you. Forgive us for
judging
when you have not given that role to us
at least yet.
Lord, help us to trust you and to know
that everyone that we will be in heaven
is there because you know and everyone
that will be lost
is there because you have the records.
Lord, please show us what it means
to exercise love and mercy even to those
that do not agree with our positions.
Help us to live as you lived and to love
as you loved. This we pray in Jesus
name. Amen. And amen.
May God bless you all.
Please stay awake. Do not go to sleep.
And may God keep your heart and your
eyes focused on him.
We're going to put the um uh link in the
chat for the afterglow. Please feel free
to uh to join us as we discuss today's
sermon, today's um Sabbath school. And
may God bless you and keep you. Um, and
we will see you again next Sabbath. God
bless.
Thank you for joining us today. If this
is your first time worshiping with us,
please check out our website at
livingmana.urch.
We are not just here for Sabbath
service. We have weekly programming too
that covers mental health, physical
health, weekly prayer service, financial
health, and proving the existence of
God. It is our desire that our
programming will continue to bless you.
Please continue to pray for us as we
fulfill God's mission to go into all the
world with the gospel of Jesus Christ.
[Music]